<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Study Extra Master – Earth&#39;s tides</title>
    <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Earth&#39;s tides on Study Extra Master</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/typoftides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/typoftides/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Tides can be classified in a number of ways, including by frequency, range, and type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Frequency&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;frequency&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#frequency&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tides can be classified by frequency based on the number of high and low tides that occur each day. The three main types of tidal frequencies are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diurnal tides:&lt;/strong&gt; One high tide and one low tide per day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semi-diurnal tides:&lt;/strong&gt; Two high tides and two low tides per day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mixed tides:&lt;/strong&gt; A combination of diurnal and semi-diurnal tides, with the number of high and low tides varying per day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Range&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;range&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#range&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tides can also be classified by range, which is the difference in height between the high and low tides. The three main types of tidal ranges are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microtidal tides:&lt;/strong&gt; A range of less than 2 meters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mesotidal tides:&lt;/strong&gt; A range of 2 to 4 meters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Macrotidal tides:&lt;/strong&gt; A range of more than 4 meters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Type&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#type&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tides can also be classified by type, based on the forces that cause them. The three main types of tides are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Astronomical tides:&lt;/strong&gt; Caused by the gravitational pull of the moon and the sun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meteorological tides:&lt;/strong&gt; Caused by atmospheric pressure changes and winds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seiches:&lt;/strong&gt; Caused by the resonant oscillation of water in enclosed or semi-enclosed bodies of water, such as lakes and bays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Examples&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;examples&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#examples&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of different types of tides:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diurnal tides:&lt;/strong&gt; Diurnal tides are common in the tropics, where the moon passes overhead twice a day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semi-diurnal tides:&lt;/strong&gt; Semi-diurnal tides are common in temperate and polar regions, where the moon passes overhead once a day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mixed tides:&lt;/strong&gt; Mixed tides are found in many coastal areas, where the shape of the coastline and the ocean basin can affect the frequency of the tides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microtidal tides:&lt;/strong&gt; Microtidal tides are found along most of the coast of California.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mesotidal tides:&lt;/strong&gt; Mesotidal tides are found along most of the coast of the United States, as well as along the coasts of Europe and Asia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Macrotidal tides:&lt;/strong&gt; Macrotidal tides are found along the coast of Canada, the Bay of Fundy, and the coast of Patagonia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Astronomical tides:&lt;/strong&gt; Astronomical tides are the most common type of tide. They are caused by the gravitational pull of the moon and the sun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meteorological tides:&lt;/strong&gt; Meteorological tides are less common than astronomical tides. They are caused by atmospheric pressure changes and winds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seiches:&lt;/strong&gt; Seiches are rare, but they can occur in enclosed or semi-enclosed bodies of water, such as lakes and bays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tides are a complex phenomenon that is influenced by a variety of factors. However, the classification of tides by frequency, range, and type can help us to better understand and predict the tides.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-Tidal Charts</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/cotidal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/cotidal/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Co-tidal charts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;co-tidal-charts&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#co-tidal-charts&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Co- Tidal Charts are a valuable tool for mariners, fishermen, coastal engineers, and climate scientists. They provide information about the tidal wave propagation, which is the movement of the tides through the oceans. This information can be used to predict the times and heights of the high and low tides, as well as the direction of the tidal currents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-tidal charts are created using a variety of data, including tide gauge data, satellite data, and computer models. The data is used to calculate the tidal wave propagation, which is then used to create the co-tidal charts. Co-tidal charts are typically divided into two types: co-phase charts and co-range charts. Co-phase charts show the time of the high and low tides, while co-range charts show the height of the high and low tides. Co-tidal charts can also be used to predict the direction of the tidal currents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Co-tidal charts are used in a variety of ways, including:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;co-tidal-charts-are-used-in-a-variety-of-ways-including&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#co-tidal-charts-are-used-in-a-variety-of-ways-including&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Navigation:&lt;/strong&gt; Mariners use co-tidal charts to plan their voyages and to avoid hazards, such as shallow water and strong currents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fishing:&lt;/strong&gt; Fishermen use co-tidal charts to find the best places to fish and to predict the movement of fish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coastal engineering:&lt;/strong&gt; Coastal engineers use co-tidal charts to design coastal structures, such as seawalls and breakwaters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Climate change research:&lt;/strong&gt; Scientists use co-tidal charts to study the effects of climate change on the tides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Here are some specific examples of how co-tidal charts are used:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;here-are-some-specific-examples-of-how-co-tidal-charts-are-used&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#here-are-some-specific-examples-of-how-co-tidal-charts-are-used&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A mariner uses a co-tidal chart to plan a voyage through a narrow channel. The chart shows the mariner when the high and low tides will occur, as well as the direction of the tidal currents. This information allows the mariner to safely navigate the channel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fisherman uses a co-tidal chart to find the best place to fish for salmon. The chart shows the fisherman when the tides will be high and low, as well as the direction of the tidal currents. This information allows the fisherman to find the best places to fish and to predict the movement of salmon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A coastal engineer uses a co-tidal chart to design a seawall. The chart shows the engineer the height of the high and low tides, as well as the direction of the tidal currents. This information allows the engineer to design a seawall that can withstand the forces of the tides and waves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A scientist uses a co-tidal chart to study the effects of climate change on the tides. The chart shows the scientist how the tides have changed over time. This information allows the scientist to study the effects of climate change on the tides and to predict how the tides will change in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-tidal charts are an essential tool for a variety of people and organizations. They provide valuable information about the tidal wave propagation, which can be used to predict the tides, plan voyages, find the best places to fish, design coastal structures, and study the effects of climate change on the tides.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishment of Datums</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/datums/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/datums/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2&gt;What is a datum?&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-is-a-datum&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-a-datum&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A datum is a reference system that is used to measure distances, elevations, and other geospatial data. Datums are important because they allow us to compare geospatial data from different sources and to create maps and charts that are accurate and consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Types of datums&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;types-of-datums&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#types-of-datums&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are two main types of datums: horizontal datums and vertical datums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Horizontal datums&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;horizontal-datums&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#horizontal-datums&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;are used to measure distances on a flat surface, such as the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface. Horizontal datums are typically based on a geodetic reference frame, which is a global network of survey markers. The most common geodetic reference frame is the World Geodetic System 1984 (WGS 84). WGS 84 is used by GPS receivers to determine their positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vertical datums&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;vertical-datums&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#vertical-datums&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;are used to measure elevations. Vertical datums are typically based on a mean sea level datum. Mean sea level is the average height of the sea&amp;rsquo;s surface over a period of time, typically 19 years. The most common vertical datum in the United States is the North American Vertical Datum of 1988 (NAVD 88). NAVD 88 is used to measure elevations for a variety of purposes, including mapping, surveying, and construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Establishment of datums&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;establishment-of-datums&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#establishment-of-datums&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Datums are established by government agencies, such as the National Geodetic Survey in the United States. These agencies use a variety of geodetic and surveying techniques to establish datums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To establish a horizontal datum, geodetic surveyors measure the positions of survey markers using a variety of techniques, such as triangulation, trilateration, and GPS. Once the positions of the survey markers have been measured, the surveyors use this data to calculate the geodetic reference frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To establish a vertical datum, geodetic surveyors measure sea levels at a network of tide gauge stations. Once the sea levels have been measured, the surveyors use this data to calculate the mean sea level datum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Maintenance of datums&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;maintenance-of-datums&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#maintenance-of-datums&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once a datum has been established, it is important to maintain it. This means regularly resurveying the geodetic reference markers and measuring sea levels. It is also important to update datums as new geodetic and surveying technologies are developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Applications of datums&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;applications-of-datums&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#applications-of-datums&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Datums are used in a wide variety of applications, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mapping:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;mapping&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#mapping&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Datums are used to create maps and charts that are accurate and consistent. For example, datums are used to create nautical charts, which are used by mariners to navigate the seas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Surveying:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;surveying&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#surveying&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Datums are used by surveyors to measure distances and elevations. For example, datums are used to survey construction sites and to create boundary maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;gps&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#gps&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Datums are used by GPS receivers to determine their positions. For example, datums are used by hikers to find their way on trails and by drivers to navigate to their destinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other examples of datums&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;other-examples-of-datums&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#other-examples-of-datums&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the horizontal and vertical datums mentioned above, there are a number of other datums that are used for specific purposes. For example, the Global Navigation Satellite System (GNSS) datum is used to coordinate the different GNSS systems, such as GPS, GLONASS, and Galileo. The International Earth Rotation and Reference Systems Service (IERS) provides a variety of datums for use in different applications, such as geodesy, astronomy, and oceanography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Datums are essential for a wide variety of applications. They allow us to measure distances, elevations, and other geospatial data accurately and consistently. Datums are established and maintained by government agencies, and they are used by a variety of people and organizations for a variety of purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Knowledge of Tides</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/tideforce/&#34; &gt;Tide Raising Forces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/equitide/&#34; &gt;The Equilibrium Tide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/gktides/moderntide/&#34; &gt;Modern Tidal Theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mean Sea Level</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/msl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/msl/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Mean sea level (MSL)
is the average height of the sea&amp;rsquo;s surface over a period of time, typically 19 years. It is a reference point for measuring elevations and changes in sea level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MSL is determined by averaging hourly tide measurements over the period of time. This average is then adjusted for the effects of non-tidal factors, such as atmospheric pressure and wind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;There are two main methods for determining MSL:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;there-are-two-main-methods-for-determining-msl&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#there-are-two-main-methods-for-determining-msl&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tide gauges:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;tide-gauges&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#tide-gauges&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tide gauges are instruments that measure the height of the sea surface at a specific location. The data from tide gauges is used to calculate MSL at that location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satellite altimetry:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;satellite-altimetry&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#satellite-altimetry&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Satellite altimetry is a remote sensing technique that uses satellites to measure the height of the sea surface. Satellite altimetry data is used to calculate global MSL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tide gauges are more accurate than satellite altimetry, but they are also more expensive to install and maintain. Satellite altimetry is less accurate than tide gauges, but it provides global coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;MSL is an important measurement for a number of reasons. It is used to:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;msl-is-an-important-measurement-for-a-number-of-reasons-it-is-used-to&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#msl-is-an-important-measurement-for-a-number-of-reasons-it-is-used-to&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measure changes in sea level:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;measure-changes-in-sea-level&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#measure-changes-in-sea-level&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MSL is used to measure changes in sea level over time. This information is used to study climate change and its effects on sea levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Map the seafloor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;map-the-seafloor&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#map-the-seafloor&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MSL is used to map the seafloor by measuring the depth of the water relative to MSL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design coastal structures:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;design-coastal-structures&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#design-coastal-structures&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MSL is used to design coastal structures, such as seawalls and breakwaters, to protect coastal communities from flooding and erosion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MSL is a dynamic measurement that is constantly changing. Sea levels are rising due to climate change, and this is causing MSL to rise as well. The rate of sea level rise is expected to accelerate in the coming decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Here are some examples of how MSL is used:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;here-are-some-examples-of-how-msl-is-used&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#here-are-some-examples-of-how-msl-is-used&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Climate change research:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;climate-change-research&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#climate-change-research&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientists use MSL measurements to study climate change and its effects on sea levels. For example, scientists have used MSL measurements to show that sea levels are rising at an accelerating rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coastal engineering:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;coastal-engineering&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#coastal-engineering&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MSL is used by coastal engineers to design coastal structures, such as seawalls and breakwaters, to protect coastal communities from flooding and erosion. For example, MSL is used to determine the height of seawalls to protect coastal communities from storm surges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Navigation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;navigation&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#navigation&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MSL is used to create nautical charts, which are used by mariners to navigate the seas. Nautical charts show the depth of the water relative to MSL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MSL is an important measurement for a variety of reasons. It is used to study climate change, design coastal structures, and create nautical charts.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidal Streams,currents and their measurement</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/tidstream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em301/tides/tidstream/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2&gt;Tidal streams and currents are both movements of water in the ocean, but they have different causes and characteristics.&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;tidal-streams-and-currents-are-both-movements-of-water-in-the-ocean-but-they-have-different-causes-and-characteristics&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#tidal-streams-and-currents-are-both-movements-of-water-in-the-ocean-but-they-have-different-causes-and-characteristics&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tidal streams&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;tidal-streams&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#tidal-streams&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;are caused by the gravitational pull of the moon and sun on the Earth&amp;rsquo;s oceans. They are predictable and follow a regular cycle, with the direction and speed of the current changing with the tides. Tidal streams are strongest in coastal areas and estuaries, where the water is confined and the tidal range is high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Currents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;currents&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#currents&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;can be caused by a variety of factors, including wind, waves, and water temperature. They can be constant or variable in direction and speed, and they can occur anywhere in the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measurement of tidal streams and currents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;measurement-of-tidal-streams-and-currents&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#measurement-of-tidal-streams-and-currents&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tidal streams and currents can be measured using a variety of methods, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current meters:&lt;/strong&gt; These instruments measure the speed and direction of the current at a specific point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ADCPs (Acoustic Doppler Current Profilers):&lt;/strong&gt; These instruments use sound waves to measure the speed and direction of the current at different depths.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Radar:&lt;/strong&gt; Radar can be used to track the movement of surface currents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satellite imagery:&lt;/strong&gt; Satellite imagery can be used to track the movement of currents over large areas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance of measuring tidal streams and currents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;importance-of-measuring-tidal-streams-and-currents&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#importance-of-measuring-tidal-streams-and-currents&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Measuring tidal streams and currents is important for a variety of reasons, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Navigation:&lt;/strong&gt; Tidal streams and currents can affect the speed and direction of ships, so it is important for mariners to know about them when planning their voyages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offshore activities:&lt;/strong&gt; Tidal streams and currents can affect the positioning and operation of offshore structures, such as oil platforms and wind turbines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fisheries management:&lt;/strong&gt; Tidal streams and currents can transport fish larvae and eggs, so it is important to understand them when managing fisheries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coastal erosion:&lt;/strong&gt; Tidal streams and currents can contribute to coastal erosion, so it is important to understand them when planning coastal protection measures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Predicting tidal streams and currents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;predicting-tidal-streams-and-currents&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#predicting-tidal-streams-and-currents&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tidal streams and currents can be predicted using a variety of mathematical models. These models take into account the gravitational forces of the moon and sun, the shape of the coastline, and the depth of the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tidal stream and current predictions are available from a variety of sources, including government agencies, private companies, and websites. These predictions can be used by mariners, offshore operators, fisheries managers, and coastal planners.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
