<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Study Extra Master – Indian Insurance</title>
    <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/indianinsurance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indian Insurance on Study Extra Master</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/indianinsurance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GOI Scheme of war risk Insurance of Marine Hulls.</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/indianinsurance/wrimhscheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/indianinsurance/wrimhscheme/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The Government of India&amp;rsquo;s (GOI) Scheme of War Risk Insurance of Marine Hulls (WRIMH) was introduced in 1976 to provide insurance coverage to Indian-owned and registered ships against war and related risks. The scheme is administered by the General Insurance Corporation of India (GIC Re), a public sector insurance company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WRIMH covers loss or damage to ships caused by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;War, civil war, revolution, rebellion, insurrection, or civil strife arising there from, or any hostile act by or against a belligerent power&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capture seizure arrest restraint or detainment, arising from risks covered under 1.1 above, and the consequences thereof or any attempt thereat
[Image of Capture seizure arrest restraint or detainment]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derelict mines torpedoes bombs or other derelict weapons of war&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any terrorist or any person acting maliciously or with a political motive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The premium for WRIMH is based on the value of the ship and the voyage route. The premium is payable to GIC Re, and the policy is issued by the designated insurance companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WRIMH has been instrumental in providing insurance coverage to Indian-owned and registered ships against war and related risks. The scheme has helped to protect the Indian shipping industry from the financial losses that can be caused by these risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WRIMH is an important part of the GOI&amp;rsquo;s efforts to promote the development of the Indian shipping industry. The scheme has helped to make India a more attractive destination for shipping investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WRIMH is a valuable tool for Indian shipowners. The scheme provides them with the peace of mind knowing that their ships are insured against war and related risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WRIMH is a well-designed and well-managed scheme. The scheme has been successful in providing insurance coverage to Indian-owned and registered ships against war and related risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WRIMH is an important part of the GOI&amp;rsquo;s efforts to promote the development of the Indian shipping industry. The scheme has helped to make India a more attractive destination for shipping investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WRIMH is a valuable tool for Indian shipowners. The scheme provides them with the peace of mind knowing that their ships are insured against war and related risks.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War risk insurance( Applicability. Features. Scope of cover- Detainment)</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/indianinsurance/wariskinsurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/indianinsurance/wariskinsurance/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marine war risk insurance is a type of insurance that covers the loss or damage to ships and their cargo caused by war, piracy, terrorism, and other related perils. It is an important type of insurance for any company that ships goods by sea, as it can help to protect the company from the financial losses that can be caused by these events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applicability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marine war risk insurance is applicable to all types of ships, including cargo ships, tankers, passenger ships, and fishing vessels. It can also be applied to offshore installations, such as oil rigs and platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marine war risk insurance is typically provided by specialist insurance companies. The cover provided by marine war risk insurance policies can vary, but it typically includes the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cover for loss or damage to ships caused by war, piracy, terrorism, and other related perils.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cover for loss or damage to cargo caused by war, piracy, terrorism, and other related perils.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cover for the cost of salvage and general average.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cover for the cost of repatriation of crew.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scope of cover: Detainment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detainment is the act of seizing or arresting a ship. Detainment can be caused by a variety of factors, including war, piracy, and sanctions. Marine war risk insurance policies typically cover the cost of detainment, including the cost of crew wages, provisions, and fuel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of benefits to having marine war risk insurance, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financial protection:&lt;/strong&gt; Marine war risk insurance can help to protect your company from the financial losses that can be caused by war, piracy, terrorism, and other related perils.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peace of mind:&lt;/strong&gt; Marine war risk insurance can give you peace of mind knowing that your ships and cargo are insured against these events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compliance with regulations:&lt;/strong&gt; In some cases, marine war risk insurance may be required by law or regulation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cost of marine war risk insurance will vary depending on a number of factors, including the type of ship, the voyage route, and the current level of risk. However, the cost of marine war risk insurance is typically a small percentage of the value of the ship and cargo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marine war risk insurance is an important type of insurance for any company that ships goods by sea. It can help to protect your company from the financial losses that can be caused by war, piracy, terrorism, and other related perils. If you are considering purchasing marine war risk insurance, you should speak to a specialist insurance broker to get a quote and to discuss your specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
