<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Study Extra Master – Indian Insurance</title>
    <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/indianinsurance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indian Insurance on Study Extra Master</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/indianinsurance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>current exclusions</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/indianinsurance/currentexclusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/indianinsurance/currentexclusions/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The specific exclusions of a war risk insurance policy will vary depending on the provider and the policy itself. However, some common exclusions include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Losses caused by war, terrorism, or civil unrest that occur in a country that is specifically excluded from the policy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Losses caused by war, terrorism, or civil unrest that occur within a certain distance of a conflict zone.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Losses caused by war, terrorism, or civil unrest that occur to certain types of property, such as contraband or nuclear weapons.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Losses caused by war, terrorism, or civil unrest that occur as a result of the insured&amp;rsquo;s own negligence.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to carefully review the exclusions of a war risk insurance policy before purchasing it. This will help to ensure that you are aware of the limitations of the policy and that you are not covered for losses that you may think are covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of current exclusions from war risk insurance policies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The war in Ukraine is excluded from many war risk insurance policies.&lt;/strong&gt; This means that businesses that operate in or ship goods to Ukraine are not covered for losses caused by the war.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The civil war in Syria is also excluded from many war risk insurance policies.&lt;/strong&gt; This means that businesses that operate in or ship goods to Syria are not covered for losses caused by the war.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001, are excluded from many war risk insurance policies.&lt;/strong&gt; This means that businesses that were affected by the attacks are not covered for losses caused by the attacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that these are just a few examples, and the specific exclusions of a war risk insurance policy will vary depending on the provider and the policy itself.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GOI Scheme of war risk Insurance of Marine Hulls.</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/indianinsurance/wrimhscheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/indianinsurance/wrimhscheme/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The Government of India&amp;rsquo;s (GOI) Scheme of War Risk Insurance of Marine Hulls (WRIMH) was introduced in 1976 to provide insurance coverage to Indian-owned and registered ships against war and related risks. The scheme is administered by the General Insurance Corporation of India (GIC Re), a public sector insurance company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WRIMH covers loss or damage to ships caused by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;War, civil war, revolution, rebellion, insurrection, or civil strife arising there from, or any hostile act by or against a belligerent power&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capture seizure arrest restraint or detainment, arising from risks covered under 1.1 above, and the consequences thereof or any attempt thereat
[Image of Capture seizure arrest restraint or detainment]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derelict mines torpedoes bombs or other derelict weapons of war&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any terrorist or any person acting maliciously or with a political motive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The premium for WRIMH is based on the value of the ship and the voyage route. The premium is payable to GIC Re, and the policy is issued by the designated insurance companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WRIMH has been instrumental in providing insurance coverage to Indian-owned and registered ships against war and related risks. The scheme has helped to protect the Indian shipping industry from the financial losses that can be caused by these risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WRIMH is an important part of the GOI&amp;rsquo;s efforts to promote the development of the Indian shipping industry. The scheme has helped to make India a more attractive destination for shipping investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WRIMH is a valuable tool for Indian shipowners. The scheme provides them with the peace of mind knowing that their ships are insured against war and related risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WRIMH is a well-designed and well-managed scheme. The scheme has been successful in providing insurance coverage to Indian-owned and registered ships against war and related risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WRIMH is an important part of the GOI&amp;rsquo;s efforts to promote the development of the Indian shipping industry. The scheme has helped to make India a more attractive destination for shipping investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WRIMH is a valuable tool for Indian shipowners. The scheme provides them with the peace of mind knowing that their ships are insured against war and related risks.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Insurance and Re Insurance Companies</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/indianinsurance/indinsur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/indianinsurance/indinsur/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;India has a strong and well-developed insurance industry, with a large number of both insurance and reinsurance companies operating in the country. The insurance industry is regulated by the Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority of India (IRDAI), which was established in 1999.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Types of Insurance Companies in India&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main types of insurance companies in India:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life insurance companies:&lt;/strong&gt; Life insurance companies provide insurance policies that cover the risk of death or disability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General insurance companies:&lt;/strong&gt; General insurance companies provide insurance policies that cover a wide range of risks, such as fire, theft, and motor vehicle accidents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leading Insurance Companies in India&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the leading insurance companies in India include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life Insurance Corporation of India (LIC):&lt;/strong&gt; LIC is the largest insurance company in India, with a market share of over 60%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HDFC Life Insurance Company Ltd:&lt;/strong&gt; HDFC Life is a private life insurance company that is a joint venture between HDFC Bank and Standard Life Aberdeen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SBI Life Insurance Company Ltd:&lt;/strong&gt; SBI Life is a private life insurance company that is a joint venture between State Bank of India and BNP Paribas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ICICI Prudential Life Insurance Company Ltd:&lt;/strong&gt; ICICI Prudential Life is a private life insurance company that is a joint venture between ICICI Bank and Prudential Plc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bharti AXA Life Insurance Company Ltd:&lt;/strong&gt; Bharti AXA Life is a private life insurance company that is a joint venture between Bharti Enterprises and AXA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leading Reinsurance Companies in India&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the leading reinsurance companies in India include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Insurance Corporation of India (GIC Re):&lt;/strong&gt; GIC Re is the largest reinsurance company in India.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New India Assurance Company Ltd:&lt;/strong&gt; New India Assurance is a public sector insurance company that also provides reinsurance services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Oriental Insurance Company Ltd:&lt;/strong&gt; The Oriental Insurance Company is another public sector insurance company that also provides reinsurance services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ICICI Lombard General Insurance Company Ltd:&lt;/strong&gt; ICICI Lombard is a private general insurance company that also provides reinsurance services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HDFC Ergo General Insurance Company Ltd:&lt;/strong&gt; HDFC Ergo is another private general insurance company that also provides reinsurance services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indian Insurance Market&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Indian insurance market is one of the fastest-growing insurance markets in the world. This is due to a number of factors, including the country&amp;rsquo;s large and growing population, rising disposable incomes, and increasing awareness of the importance of insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The insurance industry in India is expected to continue to grow in the coming years. This growth will be driven by a number of factors, including the continued growth of the Indian economy, the increasing urban population, and the increasing penetration of insurance products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Indian insurance industry is a strong and well-developed industry that is playing an increasingly important role in the country&amp;rsquo;s economy. The industry is expected to continue to grow in the coming years, driven by a number of factors, including the continued growth of the Indian economy, the increasing urban population, and the increasing penetration of insurance products.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War risk insurance( Applicability. Features. Scope of cover- Detainment)</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/indianinsurance/wariskinsurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/indianinsurance/wariskinsurance/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marine war risk insurance is a type of insurance that covers the loss or damage to ships and their cargo caused by war, piracy, terrorism, and other related perils. It is an important type of insurance for any company that ships goods by sea, as it can help to protect the company from the financial losses that can be caused by these events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applicability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marine war risk insurance is applicable to all types of ships, including cargo ships, tankers, passenger ships, and fishing vessels. It can also be applied to offshore installations, such as oil rigs and platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marine war risk insurance is typically provided by specialist insurance companies. The cover provided by marine war risk insurance policies can vary, but it typically includes the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cover for loss or damage to ships caused by war, piracy, terrorism, and other related perils.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cover for loss or damage to cargo caused by war, piracy, terrorism, and other related perils.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cover for the cost of salvage and general average.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cover for the cost of repatriation of crew.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scope of cover: Detainment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detainment is the act of seizing or arresting a ship. Detainment can be caused by a variety of factors, including war, piracy, and sanctions. Marine war risk insurance policies typically cover the cost of detainment, including the cost of crew wages, provisions, and fuel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of benefits to having marine war risk insurance, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financial protection:&lt;/strong&gt; Marine war risk insurance can help to protect your company from the financial losses that can be caused by war, piracy, terrorism, and other related perils.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peace of mind:&lt;/strong&gt; Marine war risk insurance can give you peace of mind knowing that your ships and cargo are insured against these events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compliance with regulations:&lt;/strong&gt; In some cases, marine war risk insurance may be required by law or regulation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cost of marine war risk insurance will vary depending on a number of factors, including the type of ship, the voyage route, and the current level of risk. However, the cost of marine war risk insurance is typically a small percentage of the value of the ship and cargo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marine war risk insurance is an important type of insurance for any company that ships goods by sea. It can help to protect your company from the financial losses that can be caused by war, piracy, terrorism, and other related perils. If you are considering purchasing marine war risk insurance, you should speak to a specialist insurance broker to get a quote and to discuss your specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War Risk Trading Warranty under War Risk Insurance Scheme</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/indianinsurance/warisktrading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/indianinsurance/warisktrading/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is war risk insurance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;War risk insurance is a type of insurance that covers losses caused by war, terrorism, or civil unrest. It is typically purchased by businesses that operate in or ship goods to areas that are considered to be high risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a war risk trading warranty?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A war risk trading warranty is a clause in a commercial contract that requires the buyer of a good or service to obtain war risk insurance for the good or service. This warranty is designed to protect the seller from losses caused by war, terrorism, or civil unrest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does a war risk trading warranty work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under a war risk trading warranty, the buyer is typically required to obtain war risk insurance that covers the full value of the good or service. The buyer must also provide the seller with a copy of the insurance policy. If the good or service is lost or damaged as a result of war, terrorism, or civil unrest, the buyer will be able to file a claim with the insurance company. The insurance company will then pay the seller for the loss or damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits of a war risk trading warranty&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several benefits to a war risk trading warranty for both buyers and sellers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For buyers, the benefits include:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protection from losses caused by war, terrorism, or civil unrest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peace of mind knowing that their goods or services are insured.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The ability to negotiate a lower price for the good or service since the seller is assuming some of the risk.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For sellers, the benefits include:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protection from losses caused by war, terrorism, or civil unrest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The ability to sell their goods or services to buyers in high-risk areas.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The ability to charge a higher price for the good or service since they are assuming some of the risk.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;War risk trading warranties are an important tool for businesses that operate in or ship goods to high-risk areas. They can help to protect businesses from losses caused by war, terrorism, or civil unrest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note that this information is general in nature and should not be taken as legal advice. You should always consult with an attorney to discuss the specific terms of a war risk trading warranty.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
