<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Study Extra Master – Cargo Insurance Claims</title>
    <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cargo Insurance Claims on Study Extra Master</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/sueandlabourclause/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/sueandlabourclause/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Sue And Labour Clause&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ‘sue and labour’ clause in the SG form of policy reads: ‘and in case of any loss or misfortune it shall be lawful to the assured, their factors, servants and assigns, to sue, labour, and travel for, in and about the defence, safeguards, and recovery of the said goods and merchandises, and ship, etc., or any part thereof, without prejudice to this insurance; to the charges whereof we, the assurers, will contribute…’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modern counterpart of this clause may be found, for example, in clause 11 of the Institute Time Clauses – Hulls (1/11/95):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘11.1 In case of any loss or misfortune it is the duty of the Assured and their servants and agents to take such measures as may be reasonable for the purpose of averting or minimising a loss which would be recoverable under this insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11.2…the Underwriters will contribute to charges properly and reasonably incurred by the Assured their servants or agents for such measures…’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This formulation is also retained in clause 9 of the International Hull Clauses 2003. See also clause 16 of the Institute Cargo Clauses (A) (1/1/82) or (1/1/09) (often referred to as the ‘Bailee Clause’), because it imposes a wider duty than clause 11 of the Hulls Clauses in that it requires the assured to preserve rights of action against third parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sue and labour clause probably has two components, namely:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a) A duty upon the assured to take reasonable steps to avert or minimise a loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b) An obligation upon the insurer to indemnify the assured for the costs of such steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The former component is unnecessary given that the duty is set out in section 78(4) MIA. The latter component, however, seems to be essential to the recovery of a ‘sue and labour’ expense by the assured from the insurer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Assured’s Entitlement Under The Sue And Labour Clause&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under section 78(1)MIA, where a policy contains a sue and labour clause, ‘the engagement thereby entered into is deemed to be supplementary to the contract of insurance, and the assured may recover from the insurer any expenses properly incurred pursuant to the clause…’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, if the policy contains such a clause, the assured is entitled to recover from the insurer the expenses incurred pursuant to the clause (i.e. the expenses incurred for the purpose of minimising or averting a loss (provided that they are reasonably and properly incurred)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The insurer’s liability is supplementary to his or her liability under the insurance contract (i.e. the insurer will be liable for such expenses in addition to the limit of his or her liability under the insurance contract).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a) If the insurance contract limits the insurer’s liability (by way of a valuation or a ‘sum insured’ clause) to say US$2,000,000, any sue and labour expenses are recoverable notwithstanding that the insurer is also liable for the US$2,000,000 under the insurance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b) Similarly, sue and labour expenses may be incurred even though a policy limit has been reached, subject to the terms of the contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c) It does not matter if the subject-matter of the insurance is warranted free from particular average (sections 76(2), 78(1) MIA or the insurer has paid a total loss (section 78(1) MIA). When does a right to recover ‘sue and labour’ expenses from the insurer arise (assuming the insurance contract contains a ‘sue and labour’ clause)? It appears that the following elements have to be proved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d) An insured peril was imminent or was operative. As to the meaning of an ‘imminent’ peril in the context of a clause similar to a sue and labour clause in a ‘construction all risks’ policy, the authority is the case of Gerling General Insurance Co v Canary Wharf Group plc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e) The assured or his or her agent has undertaken unusual and extraordinary steps or exertion or incurred unusual and extraordinary expense. The expense need not necessarily involve the outlay of money; a waiver of a claim which has a value in money will be sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;f) The purpose of the action or the expense must have been to preserve the insured property from loss by an insured peril. If the expense was incurred for the purpose of averting or minimizing a loss not covered by the policy, the expense is not recoverable under the sue and labour clause (section 78(3) MIA). (Where the expense is incurred for dual purposes, one of which is to prevent or minimise a loss covered by the policy.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;g) The action or expense must have been reasonable. It does not have to be successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;h) If a loss had occurred by reason of the insured peril, the loss would have been indemnifiable under the insurance contract. It is not necessary for the assured to show that the loss would very probably have occurred; there need only be a risk that the insurer would have to bear the loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the purpose of the expense is to avoid a loss which is covered under the policy and a loss which is not covered under the policy, the assured will be entitled to recover a proportionate part of the expense (Cunard Steamship Co v Marten, Kuwait Airways Corp v Kuwait Insurance Co SAK; compare the position where the expense is incurred to protect insured property and lives not insured under the policy: Royal Boskalis Westminster NV v Mountain).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As to the recovery of ransoms paid to pirates under a sue and labour clause, see Masefield AG v Amlin Corporate Member Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if the expense has been incurred illegally, then the expense may not be recovered from the insurer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As to the recovery of mitigation expenses where there was a dual purpose behind such expenditure, in the case of non-marine insurance, see Ace European Group Ltd v Standard Life Assurance Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As to the position where the expense is incurred to protect both insured property and lives not insured under the policy, see also Atlasnavios-Navegação Lda v Navigators Insurance Co Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Costs may be recovered under the sue and labour clause of a marine policy even where such costs would not be recovered as partial loss or particular average claims under the same policy: Atlasnavios-Navegação Lda v Navigators Insurance Co Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be that sue and labour costs may also constitute ‘cost of repair’ for the purpose of determining whether the insured vessel is a constructive total loss: Connect Shipping Inc v The Swedish Club (The Renos).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a loss had occurred by reason of the insured peril, the loss must have been indemnifiable under the insurance contract. As to the degree of possibility or probability of such loss occurring, see Integrated Container Service Inc v British Traders Insurance Co Ltd; see also Suez Fortune Investments Ltd v Talbot Underwriting Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sue and labour expenses may be incurred while the insured peril continues to operate, in other words until the vessel is in a place of safety (Suez Fortune Investments Ltd v Talbot Underwriting Ltd).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entitlement to recover sue and labour expenses appears to come to an end upon the issue of legal proceedings in respect of the relevant loss (Kuwait Airways Corp v Kuwait Insurance Co SAK; Atlasnavios-Navegação Lda v Navigators Insurance Co Ltd; Suez Fortune Investments Ltd v Talbot Underwriting Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Assured’s Entitlement In The Absence Of A Sue And Labour Clause&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is no sue and labour clause, the question arises whether or not the assured can recover expenses incurred for the purpose of preserving or protecting the subject-matter insured from loss caused by an insured peril in any event or on any other grounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Courts are generally sceptical towards any attempt to recover mitigation expenses in the absence of a sue and labour clause (Seele Austria GmbH &amp;amp; Co v Tokio Marine Europe Insurance Ltd).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are five possible bases upon which there might be such a recovery:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a) If the expense can be viewed as a loss resulting from the operation of the insured peril, the expense may be recovered under the policy, unless there is a break in the chain of causation (see Stanley v Western Insurance Co, The Diamond, Symington &amp;amp; Co v Union Insurance Society of Canton Ltd, Canada Rice Mills Ltd v Union Marine &amp;amp; General Insurance Co Ltd, compare Kuwait Airways Corp v Kuwait Insurance Co SAK). If the assured mistakenly believes that there is an imminent or operative peril, the assured will not be able to recover an indemnity for any expenses incurred thereby (Joseph Watson &amp;amp; Son Ltd v Firemen’s Fund Insurance Co of San Francisco).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b) The expense may be recovered as ‘salvage charges’ within the meaning of section 65 MIA. Under that section, salvage charges are charges recoverable by a salvor under ‘maritime law’ independently of a contract and do not include charges incurred under a salvage contract, which are normally recoverable under the sue and labour clause (clause 10 of the Institute Time Clauses – Hulls (1/11/95), clause 10; International Hull Clauses 2003, clause 8).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c) The expense may be recovered as a ‘general average loss’ pursuant to section 66(4) MIA. This depends on establishing a ‘general average act’ within the meaning of section 66(2) MIA (The Abt Rasha) (see clause 10 of the Institute Time Clauses – Hulls (1/11/95), clause 10; International Hull Clauses 2003, clause 8).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d) If the expense is incurred as ‘particular charges’, which are defined under section 64(2) of the MIA as ‘expenses incurred by or on behalf of the assured for the safety or preservation of the subject-matter insured, other than general average and salvage charges’. The traditional view is that particular charges are not recoverable in the absence of a sue and labour However, where the view is set out that particular charges may be recovered independently of a sue and labour clause provided that ‘it can plausibly be said that the need for the expenditure is the direct and natural result of the casualty and the MIA does not lay down a specific measure of indemnity which meets the case’. This view was referred to with apparent approval in the case of Royal Boskalis Westminster NV v Mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e) There is an argument that such expenses may be recovered as ‘mitigation damages’ or pursuant to an implied term. However, this is contrary to the decision of the Court of Appeal in Yorkshire Water v Sun Alliance &amp;amp; London Insurance Ltd. As regards the Bailee Clause, in The Netherlands Insurance Co Est 1845 Ltd v Karl Ljungberg &amp;amp; Co AB, the Privy Council found that there was an implied term entitling the assured to be reimbursed in respect of the second limb of the Bailee Clause (however, in this case, there was also a sue and labour clause).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Assured’s Duty To Mitigate: S.78(4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Section 78(4) MIA provides that ‘it is the duty of the assured and his agents, in all cases, to take such measures as may be reasonable for the purpose of averting or minimising a loss.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following attributes of section 78(4) MIA should be noted:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a) Although section 78(4) MIA speaks of a ‘duty’, this is in effect no more than a statement of the law that if the assured or his agents fail to take reasonable measures to avert or minimise a loss, that failure may be the proximate cause of the assured’s loss, in whole or in part, so that the assured would be unable to prove that that part of the loss is caused by an insured peril and would be prevented from recovering an indemnity in respect of such loss under the policy. It is comparable to the ‘duty to mitigate’ arising in respect of ordinary The failure to comply with this duty will not automatically constitute a defence to the claim (compare Currie &amp;amp; Co v The Bombay Native Insurance Co) or give rise to a claim for damages for breach of contract (The Gold Sky), unless the relevant duty can be said to arise by way of an express or implied promissory obligation (The Vasso– this case involved the ‘Bailee Clause’).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b) The word ‘agents’ is a reference to ‘agents to sue and labour’, that is, agents who have been instructed by the assured to take steps to preserve or protect the property insured and/or who are agents by Such agents generally will include the master (Currie &amp;amp; Co v The Bombay Native Insurance Co, State of the Netherlands v Youell, contra The Gold Sky).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c) The duty is one of reasonableness. The assured must act as a prudent uninsured (Integrated Container Service Inc v British Traders Insurance Co Ltd), taking into account the knowledge and experience of the assured or his or her agent (Stephen v Scottish Boatowners Mutual Insurance Association (The Talisman).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d) There is a potential conflict between sections 55(2)(a) and 78(4) MIA in that the former provision provides that unreasonable conduct on the part of the master will not prevent the assured from recovering under the policy provided that the loss has been caused by an insured peril, whereas the latter provision provides that the assured’s claim may be prejudiced if the master as the assured’s agent fails to take reasonable steps to avert or minimise the damage. In State of the Netherlands v Youell, the Court of Appeal said that this conflict is unlikely to arise and noted that if the master’s negligence is an insured peril under the policy, the conflict would not arise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e) The duty applies ‘in all cases’, suggesting that it applies even when there is no sue and labour&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;f) However, there is a question whether or not the duty applies in respect of all circumstances which are insured or only those relating to a maritime adventure (section 3 MIA).&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Average total Loss (ATL)</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/atl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/atl/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;average total loss&lt;/strong&gt; in marine cargo insurance occurs when the cost of repairing the damaged cargo or rescuing it is greater than the value of the cargo itself. In this case, the insured is entitled to claim the full value of the cargo from the insurance company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two types of average total loss:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actual total loss:&lt;/strong&gt; This occurs when the cargo is completely destroyed or lost.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constructive total loss:&lt;/strong&gt; This occurs when the cost of repairing the damaged cargo or rescuing it is greater than the value of the cargo itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To determine whether an average total loss has occurred, the insurance company will consider the following factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cost of repairing the damaged cargo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cost of rescuing the damaged cargo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The value of the cargo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the cost of repairing or rescuing the cargo is greater than the value of the cargo, then the insurance company will declare an average total loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the insured chooses to abandon the cargo, the insurance company will take ownership of the cargo and pay the insured the full value of the cargo. If the insured chooses to keep the cargo, the insurance company will pay the insured the cost of repairs, minus the value of the salvage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of average total loss in marine cargo insurance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A ship carrying a cargo of electronics sinks in a storm. The cargo is completely destroyed, so the insurance company declares an average total loss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A cargo of perishable goods is damaged in a fire on board a ship. The cost of repairing the damaged cargo is greater than the value of the cargo, so the insurance company declares an average total loss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A cargo of computers is stolen from a warehouse. The insurance company is unable to locate the stolen cargo, so it declares an average total loss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Average total loss claims are relatively rare in marine cargo insurance. However, they can be very costly for insurance companies, so it is important for insurers to carefully assess the risk of average total loss before issuing a policy.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cargo claims procedure</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/cgoclaimsproc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/cgoclaimsproc/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The cargo claims procedure is the process of filing a claim with a carrier or insurer for loss or damage to cargo. The specific steps involved in the process may vary depending on the carrier, the type of cargo, and the nature of the loss or damage. However, the general process is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notice of damage or loss:&lt;/strong&gt; The first step is to notify the carrier in writing of the damage or loss as soon as possible. This should be done within the time limits specified in the carrier&amp;rsquo;s bill of lading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation:&lt;/strong&gt; The claimant must gather all relevant documentation, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A copy of the bill of lading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A copy of the commercial invoice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A copy of the packing list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photographs of the damaged cargo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A report from a surveyor or inspector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any other documents that support the claim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Submit the claim:&lt;/strong&gt; The claim should be submitted to the carrier or insurer in writing. The claim form should include a detailed description of the damage or loss, the value of the cargo, and copies of the supporting documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigation:&lt;/strong&gt; The carrier or insurer will investigate the claim to determine if it is valid. This may involve interviewing witnesses, examining the damaged cargo, and reviewing the supporting documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Settlement:&lt;/strong&gt; If the claim is valid, the carrier or insurer will settle the claim by paying the claimant the value of the damaged or lost cargo. The amount of the settlement may be based on the actual value of the cargo, the cost of repairs, or the value of the cargo at the destination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Here are some additional tips for filing a cargo claim:&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;here-are-some-additional-tips-for-filing-a-cargo-claim&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#here-are-some-additional-tips-for-filing-a-cargo-claim&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;File the claim as soon as possible:&lt;/strong&gt; The sooner you file the claim, the more likely it is that you will be able to recover your losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gather all relevant documentation:&lt;/strong&gt; The more documentation you can provide, the stronger your claim will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be prepared to cooperate with the carrier&amp;rsquo;s investigation:&lt;/strong&gt; The carrier will need to interview you and inspect the damaged cargo in order to determine if your claim is valid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consider hiring a cargo claims attorney:&lt;/strong&gt; If your claim is large or complex, you may want to consider hiring a cargo claims attorney to help you file and process your claim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cargo claims can be complex and time-consuming to process. However, by following the steps outlined above and providing the carrier or insurer with all of the necessary documentation, you can increase your chances of recovering your losses.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constructive Total Loss</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/ctl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/ctl/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Under section 60 of the Marine Insurance Act 1906, an assured shipowner can claim for a ** constructive total loss (CTL) if the costs of repairing the damage (inclusive of salvage charges and other expenses) would be more than the value of the ship when repaired.**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of Swedish Club v Connect Shipping Inc (the “Renos”) the hull insurers challenged a claim for a CTL on the grounds that the shipowners’ calculation of repair costs included two categories of expense which shouldn’t be taken into account. The High Court and Court of Appeal rejected Swedish Club’s challenge, but their appeal to the Supreme Court was partly successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Calculating the costs at the right time&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;calculating-the-costs-at-the-right-time&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#calculating-the-costs-at-the-right-time&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The insurers first argued that the position should be assessed at the time when the shipowner gives notice of abandonment, and the calculation of costs must exclude those incurred before then. In this case the owners had incurred salvage costs and further expenses at a port of refuge before giving notice of abandonment. If those costs weren’t included in the calculation, the repair costs would be less than the vessel&amp;rsquo;s insured value and there would be no CTL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court analysed basic principles of insurance law when making its decision. In particular, the court noted the general rule that a loss under a hull and machinery policy occurs at the time of the casualty, not when the measure of indemnity is established. It followed that damage leading to a CTL was in principle the entire damage arising from the casualty from the moment that it happened, and it made no difference when the costs were incurred. On this point, the Supreme Court agreed with the lower courts that the salvage costs and other expenses incurred from the time of the casualty should be taken into account in determining whether the vessel was a CTL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SCOPIC charges&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;scopic-charges&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#scopic-charges&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The second issue the insurers raised was whether the relevant costs also included SCOPIC charges, the special compensation paid to salvors (under the addendum to the Lloyd&amp;rsquo;s Open Form salvage contract) to prevent/minimise damage to the environment following a maritime casualty. The shipowners argued that these charges should be considered as repair costs, because they were part of the salvors’ remuneration which had to be paid in order to repair the ship, and this was accepted by the lower courts. However, the Supreme Court noted that SCOPIC charges are expressly excluded from general average and are generally paid (as they were in this case) by the vessel’s P&amp;amp;I insurers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court considered that the objective of SCOPIC charges wasn’t to enable the vessel to be repaired, but to protect the shipowner against liability for environmental pollution. That was not related to the subject-matter insured by the hull and machinery policy, and was not part of the measure of the damage to the ship. On this point, therefore, the insurers’ appeal succeeded.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>extra charges</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/extrachrges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/extrachrges/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Marine insurance extra charges are additional premiums that are charged by marine insurance companies to cover risks that are considered to be higher than normal. These extra charges can be applied to both cargo insurance and hull insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some common examples of marine insurance extra charges include:&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;some-common-examples-of-marine-insurance-extra-charges-include&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#some-common-examples-of-marine-insurance-extra-charges-include&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overage extra:&lt;/strong&gt; This extra charge is applied to vessels that are more than a certain age, typically 15 years or older.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Under tonnage extra:&lt;/strong&gt; This extra charge is applied to smaller vessels, as they are considered to be more vulnerable to accidents and losses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-classification extra:&lt;/strong&gt; This extra charge is applied to vessels that are not classified by a recognized classification society.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-approval extra:&lt;/strong&gt; This extra charge is applied to vessels that are not approved by the insurance company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;War and kindred perils extra:&lt;/strong&gt; This extra charge is applied for coverage against war and related risks, such as terrorism and piracy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strikes, riots, and civil commotions (SRCC) extra:&lt;/strong&gt; This extra charge is applied for coverage against strikes, riots, and civil commotions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dangerous goods extra:&lt;/strong&gt; This extra charge is applied for coverage of dangerous goods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temperature-sensitive cargo extra:&lt;/strong&gt; This extra charge is applied for coverage of temperature-sensitive cargo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perishable cargo extra:&lt;/strong&gt; This extra charge is applied for coverage of perishable cargo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deck cargo extra:&lt;/strong&gt; This extra charge is applied for coverage of cargo that is carried on deck.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short transit extra:&lt;/strong&gt; This extra charge is applied for cargoes with a very short transit time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marine insurance extra charges are typically calculated as a percentage of the base premium. The amount of the extra charge will vary depending on the risk factor involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cargo owners can minimize marine insurance extra charges by:&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;cargo-owners-can-minimize-marine-insurance-extra-charges-by&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#cargo-owners-can-minimize-marine-insurance-extra-charges-by&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choosing a reputable and experienced freight forwarder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Packing their cargo properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoiding dangerous and perishable goods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choosing a vessel that is classified by a recognized classification society.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Declaring all risks to their insurance company in advance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By taking these steps, cargo owners can reduce the risk of an insured loss and save money on their marine insurance premiums.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forwarding charges</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/forwardchrges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/forwardchrges/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Marine cargo insurance forwarding charges are the additional costs incurred by the cargo owner to forward their cargo to its destination following an insured loss or damage. These charges are typically covered by the marine cargo insurance policy, but there may be limits or exclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some common examples of marine cargo insurance forwarding charges include:&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;some-common-examples-of-marine-cargo-insurance-forwarding-charges-include&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#some-common-examples-of-marine-cargo-insurance-forwarding-charges-include&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unloading and storage charges:&lt;/strong&gt; These charges may be incurred if the cargo needs to be unloaded from the vessel and stored before it can be forwarded to its destination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Onward transportation charges:&lt;/strong&gt; These charges cover the cost of transporting the cargo from the port of discharge to its final destination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customs clearance charges:&lt;/strong&gt; These charges may be incurred if the cargo needs to be cleared through customs before it can be forwarded to its destination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Survey fees and reconditioning costs:&lt;/strong&gt; These charges may be incurred if the cargo needs to be surveyed or reconditioned before it can be forwarded to its destination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sue and labor expenses:&lt;/strong&gt; These are expenses incurred to avert or minimize a loss from an insured peril.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be covered by marine cargo insurance, forwarding charges must be properly and reasonably incurred. The cargo owner must also be able to provide evidence of the charges incurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Here are some tips for cargo owners to minimize marine cargo insurance forwarding charges:&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;here-are-some-tips-for-cargo-owners-to-minimize-marine-cargo-insurance-forwarding-charges&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#here-are-some-tips-for-cargo-owners-to-minimize-marine-cargo-insurance-forwarding-charges&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a good relationship with your freight forwarder:&lt;/strong&gt; A good freight forwarder can help you to minimize forwarding charges by negotiating with carriers and other service providers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be prepared to provide documentation:&lt;/strong&gt; When filing a claim with your marine cargo insurance company, you will need to provide documentation of the forwarding charges incurred. This may include invoices, receipts, and bills of lading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know the terms of your insurance policy:&lt;/strong&gt; It is important to understand the terms of your marine cargo insurance policy, including the coverage for forwarding charges. This will help you to avoid any surprises when filing a claim.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal aspect of claims against the Carrier</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/legalclaimscarrier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/legalclaimscarrier/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The legal aspects of recovery against the carrier for loss or damage to cargo are governed by the terms of the bill of lading, which is the contract of carriage between the shipper and the carrier. The bill of lading typically sets out the carrier&amp;rsquo;s liability for loss or damage to cargo, as well as the shipper&amp;rsquo;s obligations to file a claim and provide documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;In general, the carrier is liable for loss or damage to cargo under the following circumstances:&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;in-general-the-carrier-is-liable-for-loss-or-damage-to-cargo-under-the-following-circumstances&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#in-general-the-carrier-is-liable-for-loss-or-damage-to-cargo-under-the-following-circumstances&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the loss or damage is caused by the carrier&amp;rsquo;s negligence: This includes negligence on the part of the carrier&amp;rsquo;s employees, agents, or subcontractors. For example, the carrier may be liable if the cargo is lost or damaged due to improper packing, handling, or storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the loss or damage is caused by an act of God: This includes natural disasters such as hurricanes, floods, earthquakes, and tornadoes. The carrier is not liable for loss or damage caused by an act of God if the carrier took reasonable precautions to prevent the loss or damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the loss or damage is caused by a public enemy: This includes war, terrorism, and piracy. The carrier is not liable for loss or damage caused by a public enemy if the carrier took reasonable precautions to prevent the loss or damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;However, the carrier may be able to limit its liability under the following circumstances:&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;however-the-carrier-may-be-able-to-limit-its-liability-under-the-following-circumstances&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#however-the-carrier-may-be-able-to-limit-its-liability-under-the-following-circumstances&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the shipper fails to properly pack or mark the cargo: The carrier is not liable for loss or damage to cargo that is improperly packed or marked if the improper packing or marking contributed to the loss or damage. For example, the carrier may not be liable for loss or damage to fragile cargo that is not properly packed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the shipper fails to declare the true value of the cargo: The carrier is not liable for loss or damage to cargo if the shipper fails to declare the true value of the cargo in the bill of lading. This is because the carrier&amp;rsquo;s liability is limited to the declared value of the cargo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the shipper fails to file a claim within the time limits specified in the bill of lading: The carrier is not liable for loss or damage to cargo if the shipper fails to file a claim with the carrier within the time limits specified in the bill of lading. These time limits are typically very short, so it is important to file a claim as soon as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the carrier may be able to avoid liability altogether if the loss or damage is caused by an inherent vice of the cargo, such as a defect in the cargo itself. For example, the carrier is not liable for loss or damage to cargo that is inherently defective, such as perishable goods that spoil due to their own nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If the shipper is able to prove that the carrier is liable for loss or damage to cargo, the shipper may be able to recover the following damages:&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;if-the-shipper-is-able-to-prove-that-the-carrier-is-liable-for-loss-or-damage-to-cargo-the-shipper-may-be-able-to-recover-the-following-damages&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#if-the-shipper-is-able-to-prove-that-the-carrier-is-liable-for-loss-or-damage-to-cargo-the-shipper-may-be-able-to-recover-the-following-damages&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The value of the lost or damaged cargo: This is the amount of money that the shipper would have received if the cargo had been delivered in good condition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cost of repairs: If the cargo can be repaired, the shipper may be able to recover the cost of repairs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The loss of profits: If the loss or damage to the cargo prevents the shipper from making a profit, the shipper may be able to recover the lost profits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other consequential damages: In some cases, the shipper may be able to recover other consequential damages, such as the cost of storing the damaged cargo or the cost of renting replacement cargo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shipper may also be able to recover attorney&amp;rsquo;s fees if the shipper is successful in its claim against the carrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Filing a claim against the carrier for loss or damage to cargo can be a complex process. It is important to consult with an attorney who specializes in cargo claims law to ensure that your claim is filed properly and that you recover the full amount of damages to which you are entitled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some additional tips for recovering against the carrier:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;File the claim as soon as possible:&lt;/strong&gt; The sooner you file the claim, the more likely it is that you will be able to recover your losses. This is because the carrier may be able to more easily investigate the claim and gather evidence if the claim is filed promptly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gather all relevant documentation:&lt;/strong&gt; The more documentation you can provide, the stronger your claim will be. This documentation should include a copy of the bill of lading, a copy of the commercial invoice, a copy of the packing list, photographs of the damaged cargo, a report from a surveyor or inspector, and any other documents that support the claim.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be prepared to cooperate with the carrier&amp;rsquo;s investigation:&lt;/strong&gt; The carrier will need to interview you and inspect the damaged cargo in order to determine if your claim is valid. It is important to be cooperative with the carrier&amp;rsquo;s investigation and to provide the carrier with all of the information that it needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Consider hiring a cargo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Particular Average</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/partavg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/partavg/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;** Particular Average is a partial damage to or loss of a ship or its cargo affecting only the Shipowner or one Cargo Owner. **&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does not include damage brought about by the ordinary action of the wind and waves, nor gradual deterioration on account of ordinary use. Furthermore, it does not include damage brought about by a voluntary act, which, if done in time of peril for the common safety, will form a General Average sacrifice.
Examples of cause of Particular Average damage are collision,&lt;br&gt;
contact (including stranding and grounding), heavy weather and fire.
Also, damages resulting from crew negligence or from a latent defect in the hull or machinery are covered under most sets of hull insurance conditions.
Whilst claims for Particular Average under a cargo policy are usually dealt with by the Insurer’s claims department, Average Adjusters are often appointed to process a claim for Particular Average under a ship’s hull &amp;amp; machinery policy. The reason for that is that issues like causation and allowances need to be addressed and dealt with by a person with detailed knowledge of the ins and outs of the different standard sets of hull insurance conditions and a whole array of special clauses that may be agreed to form part of the insurance cover.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of Losses or claims</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/cgoclimtypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/cgoclimtypes/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;There are four main types of cargo insurance claims:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Damage claims:&lt;/strong&gt; These are the most common type of cargo claim and occur when the shipment is damaged during transportation or storage. Damage can be caused by a variety of factors, such as weather conditions, accidents, and mishandling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss claims:&lt;/strong&gt; These claims are filed when the entire shipment or a portion of the shipment is lost. Loss can be caused by theft, pilferage, or misplacement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shortage claims:&lt;/strong&gt; These claims are filed when the shipment is delivered with fewer units than were originally invoiced. Shortages can be caused by theft, pilferage, or shipping errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concealed damage or shortage claims:&lt;/strong&gt; These claims are filed when the damage or shortage is not discovered until after the shipment has been delivered. Concealed damage or shortage can be caused by factors such as poor packaging or improper loading and unloading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to these four main types of claims, there are a number of other types of cargo insurance claims that can be filed. For example, claims can be filed for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contamination:&lt;/strong&gt; This occurs when the shipment is contaminated by a foreign substance, such as chemicals or hazardous materials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoilage:&lt;/strong&gt; This occurs when perishable goods spoil during transportation or storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delay:&lt;/strong&gt; This occurs when the shipment is delivered late and the insured suffers financial losses as a result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss of market:&lt;/strong&gt; This occurs when the shipment is lost or damaged and the insured is unable to sell the goods at the original market price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cargo insurance claims can be complex and time-consuming to process. It is important to work with your insurance company to file a claim and to provide all of the necessary documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips for filing a cargo insurance claim:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notify your insurance company as soon as possible.&lt;/strong&gt; The sooner you file your claim, the sooner the claims process can begin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provide all of the necessary documentation.&lt;/strong&gt; This includes the bill of lading, the commercial invoice, and any other documentation that supports your claim.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be prepared to cooperate with the insurance company&amp;rsquo;s investigation.&lt;/strong&gt; This may involve providing additional documentation or answering questions from the insurance company&amp;rsquo;s investigator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By following these tips, you can help to ensure that your cargo insurance claim is processed quickly and efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
