<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Study Extra Master – Cargo Insurance Claims</title>
    <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cargo Insurance Claims on Study Extra Master</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Average total Loss (ATL)</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/atl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/atl/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;average total loss&lt;/strong&gt; in marine cargo insurance occurs when the cost of repairing the damaged cargo or rescuing it is greater than the value of the cargo itself. In this case, the insured is entitled to claim the full value of the cargo from the insurance company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two types of average total loss:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actual total loss:&lt;/strong&gt; This occurs when the cargo is completely destroyed or lost.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constructive total loss:&lt;/strong&gt; This occurs when the cost of repairing the damaged cargo or rescuing it is greater than the value of the cargo itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To determine whether an average total loss has occurred, the insurance company will consider the following factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cost of repairing the damaged cargo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cost of rescuing the damaged cargo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The value of the cargo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the cost of repairing or rescuing the cargo is greater than the value of the cargo, then the insurance company will declare an average total loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the insured chooses to abandon the cargo, the insurance company will take ownership of the cargo and pay the insured the full value of the cargo. If the insured chooses to keep the cargo, the insurance company will pay the insured the cost of repairs, minus the value of the salvage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of average total loss in marine cargo insurance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A ship carrying a cargo of electronics sinks in a storm. The cargo is completely destroyed, so the insurance company declares an average total loss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A cargo of perishable goods is damaged in a fire on board a ship. The cost of repairing the damaged cargo is greater than the value of the cargo, so the insurance company declares an average total loss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A cargo of computers is stolen from a warehouse. The insurance company is unable to locate the stolen cargo, so it declares an average total loss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Average total loss claims are relatively rare in marine cargo insurance. However, they can be very costly for insurance companies, so it is important for insurers to carefully assess the risk of average total loss before issuing a policy.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constructive Total Loss</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/ctl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/ctl/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Under section 60 of the Marine Insurance Act 1906, an assured shipowner can claim for a ** constructive total loss (CTL) if the costs of repairing the damage (inclusive of salvage charges and other expenses) would be more than the value of the ship when repaired.**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of Swedish Club v Connect Shipping Inc (the “Renos”) the hull insurers challenged a claim for a CTL on the grounds that the shipowners’ calculation of repair costs included two categories of expense which shouldn’t be taken into account. The High Court and Court of Appeal rejected Swedish Club’s challenge, but their appeal to the Supreme Court was partly successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Calculating the costs at the right time&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;calculating-the-costs-at-the-right-time&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#calculating-the-costs-at-the-right-time&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The insurers first argued that the position should be assessed at the time when the shipowner gives notice of abandonment, and the calculation of costs must exclude those incurred before then. In this case the owners had incurred salvage costs and further expenses at a port of refuge before giving notice of abandonment. If those costs weren’t included in the calculation, the repair costs would be less than the vessel&amp;rsquo;s insured value and there would be no CTL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court analysed basic principles of insurance law when making its decision. In particular, the court noted the general rule that a loss under a hull and machinery policy occurs at the time of the casualty, not when the measure of indemnity is established. It followed that damage leading to a CTL was in principle the entire damage arising from the casualty from the moment that it happened, and it made no difference when the costs were incurred. On this point, the Supreme Court agreed with the lower courts that the salvage costs and other expenses incurred from the time of the casualty should be taken into account in determining whether the vessel was a CTL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SCOPIC charges&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;scopic-charges&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#scopic-charges&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The second issue the insurers raised was whether the relevant costs also included SCOPIC charges, the special compensation paid to salvors (under the addendum to the Lloyd&amp;rsquo;s Open Form salvage contract) to prevent/minimise damage to the environment following a maritime casualty. The shipowners argued that these charges should be considered as repair costs, because they were part of the salvors’ remuneration which had to be paid in order to repair the ship, and this was accepted by the lower courts. However, the Supreme Court noted that SCOPIC charges are expressly excluded from general average and are generally paid (as they were in this case) by the vessel’s P&amp;amp;I insurers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court considered that the objective of SCOPIC charges wasn’t to enable the vessel to be repaired, but to protect the shipowner against liability for environmental pollution. That was not related to the subject-matter insured by the hull and machinery policy, and was not part of the measure of the damage to the ship. On this point, therefore, the insurers’ appeal succeeded.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of Losses or claims</title>
      <link>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/cgoclimtypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.anirbanmarine.in/docs/partc/em303/cargoinsuranceclaims/cgoclimtypes/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;There are four main types of cargo insurance claims:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Damage claims:&lt;/strong&gt; These are the most common type of cargo claim and occur when the shipment is damaged during transportation or storage. Damage can be caused by a variety of factors, such as weather conditions, accidents, and mishandling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss claims:&lt;/strong&gt; These claims are filed when the entire shipment or a portion of the shipment is lost. Loss can be caused by theft, pilferage, or misplacement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shortage claims:&lt;/strong&gt; These claims are filed when the shipment is delivered with fewer units than were originally invoiced. Shortages can be caused by theft, pilferage, or shipping errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concealed damage or shortage claims:&lt;/strong&gt; These claims are filed when the damage or shortage is not discovered until after the shipment has been delivered. Concealed damage or shortage can be caused by factors such as poor packaging or improper loading and unloading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to these four main types of claims, there are a number of other types of cargo insurance claims that can be filed. For example, claims can be filed for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contamination:&lt;/strong&gt; This occurs when the shipment is contaminated by a foreign substance, such as chemicals or hazardous materials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoilage:&lt;/strong&gt; This occurs when perishable goods spoil during transportation or storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delay:&lt;/strong&gt; This occurs when the shipment is delivered late and the insured suffers financial losses as a result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss of market:&lt;/strong&gt; This occurs when the shipment is lost or damaged and the insured is unable to sell the goods at the original market price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cargo insurance claims can be complex and time-consuming to process. It is important to work with your insurance company to file a claim and to provide all of the necessary documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips for filing a cargo insurance claim:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notify your insurance company as soon as possible.&lt;/strong&gt; The sooner you file your claim, the sooner the claims process can begin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provide all of the necessary documentation.&lt;/strong&gt; This includes the bill of lading, the commercial invoice, and any other documentation that supports your claim.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be prepared to cooperate with the insurance company&amp;rsquo;s investigation.&lt;/strong&gt; This may involve providing additional documentation or answering questions from the insurance company&amp;rsquo;s investigator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By following these tips, you can help to ensure that your cargo insurance claim is processed quickly and efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
