<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Study Extra Master – Port Planning</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/partc/em302/prtpln/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Port Planning on Study Extra Master</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/docs/partc/em302/prtpln/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>COMMISSIONING OF A NON-MAJOR PORT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/partc/em302/prtpln/nonmajorprtcommissioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/partc/em302/prtpln/nonmajorprtcommissioning/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2&gt;Preamble,&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;preamble&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#preamble&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Commissioning is the last and final step in a port project. It is the end of the PERT chart of the project. After receiving the approval of the pre-commission check list from the State maritime board inspection team the process for commissioning of the port is set in motion. The port is thrown open to navigation, sea trade and commerce only after the commissioning process is over with every approval is obtained from concerned and relevant authorities.
Following ITEMS are required to be complete in all respects for commissioning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Land Estate based Infrastructures.&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;land-estate-based-infrastructures&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#land-estate-based-infrastructures&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;State Government Gazette declaration of Land ward limits under port jurisdiction. (Marking of co-ordinates on land map of the area)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completion of ISPS security wall and all the relevant ancillary structures and manning requirements as per ISPS code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registration of the PORT with Immigration and Port Health Authority (PHO) as per Central Government regulations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dealation of Notification of opening of the Port by Central Customs Board in the National Gazette as public information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IMO -Notification of opening of port for sea trade and commerce by DGS through NA&amp;rsquo;s office.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Port infrastructure with approved and certified Fire Fighting Equipment ready for use for cargo handling and stowage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Readiness of external Road and Rail connectivity of the port.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal port-road and rail traffic management system in place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organization officials in place as per Organization Chart submitted to State Maritime Board.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appointment of Conservators with all contact details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appointment of Harbour Master and qualified pilots with license&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Function Cargo gear and equipment with technical and manning details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Safety and Security Signage in all places as required for port operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of cargoes that port handles to be made public.
15.Handy Information for port users with Details of all Cargo Terminals and cargo berths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Details of all port documentation related to Inward/ Outward movements of ships calling at the port.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complied information available for public use on Port Data Base MIS of port users, ship agents, stevedores, shipping companies, Freight forwarders, ship repairers, ship chandlers and other related providers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Valid ISPS &amp;amp; NSPC, COE certifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Water front limits assets&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;water-front-limits-assets&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#water-front-limits-assets&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Details of Maximum size of ship permissible to enter the port.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Details of all berths that are available for various types of vessels visiting the port for port users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daily Meteorological forecast for port users and shipmasters. . Daily Tidal information for shipping agents and shipmasters. 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PORT chart by NHO available for ships. With all port entry information on it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Availability of facilities for maintenance of CD depth in the port main channel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adequate Port Flotilla crafts to carryout pilotage, towages, tug support, mooring and berthing operations at all times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day &amp;amp; Night Navigation facilities to carry out ship entry/Exit operations in least transit time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Services of trained PFSO to carry out all security obligations under ISPS code in the port limits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copies of DMP, OIL-Spill Containment Plan available at all operational sits as identified.
11.VTMS and Port signal station in full operational state.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Details of all services offered by the port for ships and port users to be available on port data base in MIS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy availability of Port chart produced by NHO for any port user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ship&amp;rsquo;s Arrival/ Departure&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;ships-arrival-departure&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#ships-arrival-departure&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every ship to be provided with Passge plan for entry into the port.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fairway buoy with Racon to be placed at Pick Up pilotage grounds,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pilot-Waiting anchorages to be marked. For day/night use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arrival formalities papers are to be as per FAL convention. (Read note)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;INFORMATION TO PORT USERS VIA PRESS/MEDIA&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;information-to-port-users-via-pressmedia&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#information-to-port-users-via-pressmedia&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A port is commissioned in a public function held in the presence of all potential port users, stake holders, ship owners, Hinterland industrialists, port related industries service providers, shipping agents, press and leading government officials from shipping ministry, Immigration, Customs, PHO organizations and press/media to give wide publicity to being commissioned for public use and benefit.
Commissioning procedure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Port House Flag.&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;port-house-flag&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#port-house-flag&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every port has its own unique house flag. It is unveiled on the commissioning day and thereafter flown on the port Administrative office on daily basis along with the National Flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Main Entry gate of the port.&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;main-entry-gate-of-the-port&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#main-entry-gate-of-the-port&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every non-major port main entry gate must be manned as per ISPS code standards. The passes are issued on a designated colour code basis approved by the port authority for every type of port user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Signage.&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;signage&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#signage&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the commissioning day all the safety and security signage must be in their designated spaces and spots. The internal port traffic area should have all the traffic related signage to guide the heavy truck traffic of the port. Parking areas for different usage should be well accessible for day/night use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Drainage&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;drainage&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#drainage&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The port drainage should be tried out so that accidental flooding by rain or liquid cargo etc is well avoided. The drainage spots should be properly covered by strong iron manhole protection covers. The affeulent discharge from port drainage should be discharged in the port waters with poillution norms (at 5ppm)without any traces of oil or mercury substances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Testing of FFE and apparatus.&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;testing-of-ffe-and-apparatus&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#testing-of-ffe-and-apparatus&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the day of commissioning all the FFE and apparatus must be in place and in absolute condition of readiness to fight fire within port limits as well as in immediate neighbourhood under mutual aid scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Arrival and entry of first Ship&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;arrival-and-entry-of-first-ship&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#arrival-and-entry-of-first-ship&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The agents of the identified and designated ship is called to the Harbour master&amp;rsquo;s office 48 hrs before the arrival of the ahip at the pilotage grounds. A detailed passage plan is provided to the agent to forward the same to the Master of the ship o guide him to the port entry point off the Fairway buoy. For safety and ease of entry a day time berthing is arranged. The passage plan includes all the navigational and port entry information so that Master can prepare all the documents under FAL convention. The pilotage, berthing and mooring procedures are explained in details to the Master for safety and security purposes. ISPS level of security prevailing is conveyed to the Master so that the ship and the port are at same level. The designated pilot carries the port entry chart by NHO and hands it over to the Master of the ship. The ship is requested to hoist the International codes of signals as required for port entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Readiness of Terminal and the Jetty to receive the first Ship&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;readiness-of-terminal-and-the-jetty-to-receive-the-first-ship&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#readiness-of-terminal-and-the-jetty-to-receive-the-first-ship&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The terminal manager and Jetty-in-charge are provided with all the technical iformation of the ship and deatisl of the cargo to be handled. The main cargo gear and all the ancillary handling and support equipment is kept ready to start the work immediately after the ship is cleared inward by PHO,Customs and Immigration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Support Services.&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;support-services&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#support-services&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;All the supporting services offered by the port in its inaugural manifesto are geared up to serve the ship as per Master&amp;rsquo;s request in the ETA message.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Costing of New Berth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/partc/em302/prtpln/newberthcosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/partc/em302/prtpln/newberthcosting/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The costing given below is actual construction cost of all infrastructure to be put up by the port and it does not include nor refer to any other cost of any other items to be put up by the clients.
SL. No|Item|Cost|Remark|
1|This amount excludes the following in red but includes only actual construction cost payable to the contractor
This civil works cost that will be borne by the port has been estimated in consultation with port engineer as well as with out source expert who is involved in constructing the berth in Mumbai port.
This cost does not include mob/ demob associated with such projects, engineering designs, approvals, site surveys, test seabores, soil tests and other requirements of civil engineering prior to commencement of such construction projects.|27.0 Crores|Cost of Fenders on 2 Berthing Dolphins + Bollards on each of 4 Mooring Dolphins and 2 Berthing Dolphins + Quick Release Hooks on each Berthing Dolphin|&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2|4 Mooring Dolphins, 2 Berthing Dolphins along with service platform 75m x 30 m single deck with fire monitor towers each 15 m height built on each Berthing Dolphin The cost reflects use of all piles of 24m length and 1400 mm dia throughout all structures.
These items are exclusive of the above mentioned civil cost and they are designed as per loads for largest vessel in DWT to use the berth.|3.5 Crores|
3|Fire fighting requirements at the berth only which are under OISD 156 rules if applicable|
5.0 Crores|
Foam tanks, fire water curtain of 15 m height for the entire length of 75 m of the service platform, hydrants and nozzles on the service platform as well as approach trestle, fire service lines from main pump house etc. Additional pump required in the present pump house and some extra fire water lines with valves. The pipeline route within the port area along the|&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSPC/SPS CHECK LIST FOR NON-MAJOR PORT&#39;S APPROVAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/partc/em302/prtpln/newprtapprovalchklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/partc/em302/prtpln/newprtapprovalchklist/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Name of the Port
Name of Ministry
Name of the Maritime Board
Name of the Organizational Head
Limits of the port including Inland vessels limits if any&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The items required to be inspected to grant approval&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;the-items-required-to-be-inspected-to-grant-approval&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-items-required-to-be-inspected-to-grant-approval&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;i.    A copy of organizational chart
ii.   Appointment of conservators -
iii.  Appointment of Harbour Master &amp;amp; Pilots-
iv.   List of cargoes to be handled including the IMDG in packet form or in containers-
v.    Maximum size of the vessels to be berth-
vi.   Number of berths for various types of vessels details including the depths
vii.  Prevailing weather conditions and tides (range) &amp;amp; currents details-
viii. Details on Navigational aids onshore and offshore for safe navigation-
ix.   Facilities for maintenance of channels-
x.    Length &amp;amp; width of the channel-
xi.   Size of turning circle-
xii.  Contingency planning arrangement-
xiii. Provision for Hydrographic / Bathymetric survey-
xiv.  Number of tugs and other port crafts with details on the bollard pull/power-
xv.   Arrangements of port/storm signals-
xvi.  Arrangements for security measures under ISPS code-
xvii. Preventing measures for Oil pollution such as establishment of Oil pollution Sec board/reception facilities etc-OIL-spill plan.
xviii. Type of fendering system-
xix.   A provision for local navigational warning system-
xx.    A provision for monitoring prevailing weather system-
xxi.   A provision for AIS under Security system-
xii.   A provision for VTIMS-
xiii.  Summary of rules applicable to the port Sop
xxiv.  Annual budget for the maintenance of Navigational aids-
xxv.   Provision of facilities for passengers if any-
xxvi.  Provision for port of refuge and facilities to affect emergency repairs-
xxvii. Basic repairing facilities such as dedicated anchorages or berths, repair yards &amp;amp; dry-docks-
xxviii.Provisions for facilities for ships such as Water, bunkers, suppilies &amp;amp; crew change
xxix.  Nearest Airport (National/International)-Railway stations-Road Transport-Ferry service-&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parameters for preparation of Techno-Economic Feasibility Study</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/partc/em302/prtpln/feasibilitystudy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/partc/em302/prtpln/feasibilitystudy/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2&gt;The basis of selection of site for the proposed project&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;the-basis-of-selection-of-site-for-the-proposed-project&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-basis-of-selection-of-site-for-the-proposed-project&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Details of the site:&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;details-of-the-site&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#details-of-the-site&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;a. Fore Shore and Back-up land
b. Details of climatic and sea conditions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cargo Handling/Transport capacity:&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;cargo-handlingtransport-capacity&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#cargo-handlingtransport-capacity&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;a. Locational advantage
b. The past and present positions of cargo handling in this area
c. Projection of traffic at proposed jetty d. Type of commodity to be handled
e. Written consents from Importer/exporter/customers for handling cargo through proposed jetty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Infrastructure facilities:&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;infrastructure-facilities&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#infrastructure-facilities&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;a. No. of proposed berths
b. Dimension of berth/s
c. Cargo handling machinery
d. Navigational Aids
e. Fire fighting equipments
f. Approach channel dimensions
g. Port crafts
h. Electricity/Water supply/Sewage Disposal
i. Roads and Railways
j. Pollution prevention appliances
5. Environmental Aspects
6. Details of Estimated project cost&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Financial Analysis:&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;financial-analysis&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#financial-analysis&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;a. Revenue Estimation
b. Financial arrangement for the project
c. Financial analysis
d. Sensitivity analysis
e. Assured annual income to MMB
8. Any other relevant information&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
