<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Study Extra Master – Geology and Oceanography</title>
    <link>https://anirbanmarine.github.io/extra/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geology and Oceanography on Study Extra Master</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://anirbanmarine.github.io/extra/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Active geological processes</title>
      <link>https://anirbanmarine.github.io/extra/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/actgeo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anirbanmarine.github.io/extra/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/actgeo/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2&gt;What are Active Geological processes?&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-are-active-geological-processes&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-are-active-geological-processes&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Active geological processes are the forces that are constantly shaping and changing the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface. These processes can be slow and gradual, like erosion, or they can be sudden and catastrophic, like volcanic eruptions and earthquakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Here are some examples of active geological processes:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;here-are-some-examples-of-active-geological-processes&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#here-are-some-examples-of-active-geological-processes&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Volcanoes&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;volcanoes&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#volcanoes&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Volcanoes are openings in the Earth&amp;rsquo;s crust that allow molten rock, ash, and gases to escape. When a volcano erupts, it can release a tremendous amount of energy, causing widespread destruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Earthquakes&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;earthquakes&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#earthquakes&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earthquakes are caused by the sudden release of energy in the Earth&amp;rsquo;s crust. This energy can be released by the movement of tectonic plates, or by the eruption of a volcano. Earthquakes can cause widespread damage to buildings and infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Erosion&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;erosion&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#erosion&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Erosion is the process of wearing away and transporting rock and soil. It can be caused by wind, water, ice, and gravity. Erosion is a natural process that helps to shape the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface, but it can also be a problem, especially in areas where it is accelerated by human activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Glaciations&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;glaciations&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#glaciations&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Glaciations are periods of time when the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface is covered in ice sheets and glaciers. Glaciations can last for millions of years, and they have a significant impact on the Earth&amp;rsquo;s climate and environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are just a few examples of the many active geological processes that are shaping the Earth today. These processes are essential for maintaining the planet&amp;rsquo;s habitability, but they can also pose a threat to human life and property. It is important to understand these processes and how to mitigate their risks.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earth&#39;s status and Earth&#39;s interior age</title>
      <link>https://anirbanmarine.github.io/extra/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/earthintro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anirbanmarine.github.io/extra/docs/partc/em301/oceanogeo/earthintro/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2&gt;The Earth&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;the-earth&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-earth&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earth is a terrestrial planet in the Solar System, the third planet from the Sun. It is the only astronomical object known to support life. Earth is a sphere with a slightly flattened diameter of about 12,742 kilometers (7,918 mi). Its mass is about 5.972 × 10^24 kilograms (1.317 × 10^25 lb). Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere is composed of 78.09% nitrogen, 20.95% oxygen, 0.93% argon, 0.04% carbon dioxide, and small amounts of other gases. Earth&amp;rsquo;s hydrosphere covers about 71% of its surface and is essential for life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Earth&amp;rsquo;s interior is divided into three main layers:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;earths-interior-is-divided-into-three-main-layers&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#earths-interior-is-divided-into-three-main-layers&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crust is the outermost layer and is made up of solid rock. It is about 5 to 70 kilometers (3 to 43 mi) thick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mantle is the middle layer and is made up of molten rock. It is about 2,900 kilometers (1,800 mi) thick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core is the innermost layer and is made up of solid iron and nickel. It is about 7,000 kilometers (4,300 mi) thick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Earth&amp;rsquo;s interior age&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;earths-interior-age&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#earths-interior-age&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The age of Earth&amp;rsquo;s interior is estimated to be about 4.54 billion years old. This is based on the age of meteorites, which are thought to have formed from the same material as the early Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Scientists have used a variety of methods to estimate the age of Earth&amp;rsquo;s interior, including:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;scientists-have-used-a-variety-of-methods-to-estimate-the-age-of-earths-interior-including&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#scientists-have-used-a-variety-of-methods-to-estimate-the-age-of-earths-interior-including&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radiometric dating: This method uses the decay of radioactive isotopes to determine the age of rocks and minerals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paleomagnetism: This method studies the magnetic field of the Earth as it has changed over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geochronology: This method studies the layering of rocks to determine their relative ages.
These methods have all given similar ages for Earth&amp;rsquo;s interior, suggesting that it formed about 4.54 billion years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earth is a dynamic planet with a complex interior. Scientists are still learning about the age and composition of Earth&amp;rsquo;s interior, but they have made significant progress in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
