<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Study Extra Master – Average Adjustment</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/partc/em303/averageadjustment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Average Adjustment on Study Extra Master</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/docs/partc/em303/averageadjustment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/partc/em303/averageadjustment/addback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/partc/em303/averageadjustment/addback/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2&gt;Diving Deeper into Addbacks in Marine Insurance: A Comprehensive Exploration&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;diving-deeper-into-addbacks-in-marine-insurance-a-comprehensive-exploration&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#diving-deeper-into-addbacks-in-marine-insurance-a-comprehensive-exploration&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;My previous response provided a basic overview of addbacks in average adjusting for marine insurance. Let&amp;rsquo;s now take a deeper dive into this intricate concept, exploring its nuances and implications in greater detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beyond the Basics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Types of Addbacks:&lt;/strong&gt; We discussed several common examples like salvage charges and special charges. However, the list of potential addbacks extends further. Specific examples can include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Port charges incurred due to a general average incident:&lt;/strong&gt; If entering a specific port becomes necessary for repairs or salvaging operations related to the average sacrifice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wages and provisions for crew during detention:&lt;/strong&gt; Crew expenses incurred while the ship is detained following a general average incident, waiting for repairs or further instructions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Damage to the sacrificing vessel beyond the general average:&lt;/strong&gt; If the vessel that made the sacrifice sustains additional damage not directly related to the common safety, those costs might be considered an addback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Determining Eligibility:&lt;/strong&gt; Not all expenses automatically qualify as addbacks. They must meet specific criteria to be considered distinct from the general average sacrifice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Direct benefit to a specific interest:&lt;/strong&gt; The expense must primarily benefit a particular party&amp;rsquo;s property, not the common safety of the entire voyage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No causal connection to the general average:&lt;/strong&gt; The expense wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have occurred had the general average situation not arisen, but it must not be a direct consequence of the chosen sacrifice itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reasonable and necessary:&lt;/strong&gt; The expense incurred must be deemed reasonable and necessary under the circumstances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact on Average Adjusting:&lt;/strong&gt; Addbacks play a crucial role in the average adjusting process, influencing various aspects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calculation of General Average Contribution:&lt;/strong&gt; By excluding addbacks from the total claims, the general average contribution for each party is reduced, making it fairer for those incurring specific expenses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivation for Prompt Action:&lt;/strong&gt; Knowing that certain expenses will be reimbursed encourages parties to take swift action during emergencies, potentially minimizing overall losses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparency and Fairness:&lt;/strong&gt; Clearly defined rules for addbacks enhance the transparency and fairness of the average adjusting process, minimizing disputes and misunderstandings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal and Policy Considerations:&lt;/strong&gt; The intricacies of addbacks are often outlined in marine insurance policies and relevant maritime laws. Consulting with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Average adjusters:&lt;/strong&gt; These professionals possess specialized expertise in navigating the complexities of average adjusting and addbacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maritime lawyers:&lt;/strong&gt; Lawyers with expertise in maritime law can provide legal guidance regarding specific addback claims and potential disputes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, addbacks are not just a simple accounting exercise but a crucial element ensuring fairness and efficiency in marine insurance. Understanding their nuances and legal implications empowers various stakeholders to navigate challenging situations with greater clarity and confidence. I hope this expanded explanation sheds further light on this fascinating aspect of marine insurance. Feel free to ask if you have any further questions or want to explore specific aspects in even greater detail.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Average Application</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/partc/em303/averageadjustment/ga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/partc/em303/averageadjustment/ga/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is General Average?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-is-general-average&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-general-average&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;============================&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(GA)&lt;/strong&gt; loss may occur, for example, when:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;general-average-ga-loss-may-occur-for-example-when&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#general-average-ga-loss-may-occur-for-example-when&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part of the cargo is sacrificed to save the entire venture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part of the vessel is sacrificed to save the entire venture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship and cargo are saved by unloading and reloading a stranded vessel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Water used to extinguish a fire, damages cargo (damage by fire would not be general average)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cargo is lost due to it being used a fuel because no other is available, this may only be applicable if the action is undertaken to save the whole venture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principle behind &lt;strong&gt;General Average&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(GA)&lt;/strong&gt; is that as, all the parties benefited from the sacrifice, they should all contribute to the cost of saving the venture in proportion to the value of their property. To establish each party’s contribution, the list of expenses is passed to specialists known as &lt;strong&gt;Average Adjusters&lt;/strong&gt;. To ensure that all the parties involved pay their share, their cargo is only released in exchange for an &lt;strong&gt;Average Bond&lt;/strong&gt; plus in some cases an &lt;strong&gt;Average Guarantee&lt;/strong&gt;. The latter document will be provided by the cargo owner’s insurers and if it is not forthcoming the carrying line may demand an actual cash deposit from the consignee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(GA)&lt;/strong&gt; is a highly complex subject. The practical steps, which have to be undertaken by agents attending ships, which have declared &lt;strong&gt;General Average&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(GA)&lt;/strong&gt;, are contained in the Maritime Insurance courses that are covering &lt;strong&gt;General Average&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(GA)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;general-average-ga-is-a-highly-complex-subject-the-practical-steps-which-have-to-be-undertaken-by-agents-attending-ships-which-have-declared-general-average-ga-are-contained-in-the-maritime-insurance-courses-that-are-covering-general-average-ga&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#general-average-ga-is-a-highly-complex-subject-the-practical-steps-which-have-to-be-undertaken-by-agents-attending-ships-which-have-declared-general-average-ga-are-contained-in-the-maritime-insurance-courses-that-are-covering-general-average-ga&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(GA)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;general-average-ga&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#general-average-ga&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average&lt;/strong&gt; is a principle in maritime law where, in the event of a voluntary and necessary sacrifice of part of the ship or cargo (or incurring of extraordinary expenses) to safeguard the remaining property during a perilous situation, all parties involved in the voyage contribute to the losses in proportion to their interests.&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;general-average-is-a-principle-in-maritime-law-where-in-the-event-of-a-voluntary-and-necessary-sacrifice-of-part-of-the-ship-or-cargo-or-incurring-of-extraordinary-expenses-to-safeguard-the-remaining-property-during-a-perilous-situation-all-parties-involved-in-the-voyage-contribute-to-the-losses-in-proportion-to-their-interests&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#general-average-is-a-principle-in-maritime-law-where-in-the-event-of-a-voluntary-and-necessary-sacrifice-of-part-of-the-ship-or-cargo-or-incurring-of-extraordinary-expenses-to-safeguard-the-remaining-property-during-a-perilous-situation-all-parties-involved-in-the-voyage-contribute-to-the-losses-in-proportion-to-their-interests&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In simpler terms, if a ship encounters a dangerous situation at sea and it becomes necessary to jettison (throw overboard) part of the cargo to save the ship and the rest of its cargo, then the loss of that jettisoned cargo is shared among all the cargo owners and the shipowner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rationale behind the principle is that all interests (ship, cargo, and freight) benefit from the sacrifices or expenditures made, and thus they should all contribute to the loss or expense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example: Imagine a ship carrying cargo from three different merchants: A, B, and C. During a storm, it becomes necessary to throw overboard some of Merchant A’s cargo to lighten the ship and prevent it from sinking. After the voyage is over, rather than Merchant A bearing the entire loss of his jettisoned cargo, all three merchants (A, B, and C) and possibly the shipowner would contribute to compensate for the loss based on the value of their respective cargos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual calculations and apportionment of contributions are complex and often require the involvement of average adjusters, professionals specialized in handling General Average claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When a General Average act occurs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;when-a-general-average-act-occurs&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#when-a-general-average-act-occurs&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a General Average act occurs, various steps are usually followed to ensure that the contributions are fairly assessed and collected:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Declaration of General Average&lt;/strong&gt;: Once an event has taken place that may give rise to a general average, the shipowner will declare a General Average. This usually happens when the ship safely reaches its next port after the event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Average Adjusters&lt;/strong&gt;: The shipowner will appoint an average adjuster. These are specialized professionals who calculate the contributions owed by each party. The adjuster will analyze all relevant documents, determine the value of each shipment onboard, ascertain the extent of losses, and then calculate how much each party should contribute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average Guarantee&lt;/strong&gt;: Before cargo is released at the destination port, cargo owners usually have to provide a General Average Guarantee. This is a promise to pay their contribution once the final amount is determined by the average adjuster. This guarantee can be given in various forms like a cash deposit, a bank guarantee, or an insurance company’s guarantee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average Bond&lt;/strong&gt;: This is a signed bond provided by cargo owners, promising to pay any contribution required. The bond may or may not be accompanied by a cash deposit or other guarantee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average Statement&lt;/strong&gt;: Once the average adjuster has finished their calculations, they’ll issue a General Average Statement detailing the contributions owed by each party. This could take months or even years, especially if the situation is complex.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Payment&lt;/strong&gt;: Upon receiving the General Average Statement, the parties involved will pay their respective contributions. If a cargo owner has insurance, their marine insurance policy may cover the General Average contribution, and thus, the insurer would handle the payment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principle of General Average, with its roots in ancient maritime customs, is a fascinating aspect of maritime law. It underscores the mutual venture of sea voyages and the shared risks among those involved. However, the intricacies of settling General Average claims can be complicated, necessitating experienced professionals to ensure fairness and accuracy in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average (GA) in the Modern World&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;general-average-ga-in-the-modern-world&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#general-average-ga-in-the-modern-world&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today’s globalized trade environment, the practice of General Average remains relevant, but it has seen certain criticisms and challenges:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complexity&lt;/strong&gt;: Given the intricate nature of international trade, with multiple parties, insurances, and jurisdictions involved, the General Average process can become extremely complex. Sometimes, disputes arise regarding the necessity of the sacrifice, the value of the goods, or even the amount to be apportioned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delays&lt;/strong&gt;: As mentioned, the resolution of a General Average claim can sometimes take years. This can be frustrating for cargo owners, especially when a large sum of their money might be tied up in guarantees or deposits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insurance Implications&lt;/strong&gt;: Most shippers have marine cargo insurance that covers General Average contributions. This is critical because, without insurance, the shipper could be facing a substantial out-of-pocket expense in the event of a General Average act. It’s always wise for shippers to thoroughly review their insurance policies to understand their coverages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YORK-ANTWERP Rules&lt;/strong&gt;: To standardize and simplify the General Average process, the international shipping community has adopted the YORK-ANTWERP Rules. These rules, initially adopted in 1890 and periodically updated since then, provide a set of guidelines on how General Average should be declared, adjusted, and settled. However, it’s important to note that for these rules to be applicable, the charter party or bill of lading must explicitly state that the YORK-ANTWERP Rules apply.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alternatives&lt;/strong&gt;: Some within the shipping industry argue that General Average is an outdated concept, given the advancements in shipbuilding, navigation, and maritime safety. They suggest that improved risk assessment and more comprehensive insurance coverages could eventually replace the need for General Average. While this remains a topic of debate, for now, General Average continues to be an integral part of maritime law and trade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principle of General Average showcases the shared risks and responsibilities of maritime voyages. For anyone involved in maritime trade, understanding the nuances of General Average is essential, not only from a legal standpoint but also from a risk management and financial perspective. The dynamic nature of international trade, combined with advancements in technology and infrastructure, may shape the future of this ancient principle, but its foundational ethos of shared sacrifice in the face of danger remains as relevant as ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When does General Average (GA) occur?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;when-does-general-average-ga-occur&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#when-does-general-average-ga-occur&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Average occurs when two specific criteria are met during a maritime voyage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Voluntary Sacrifice&lt;/strong&gt;: This means that a deliberate action was taken to protect the vessel and its cargo. Examples include jettisoning (throwing overboard) cargo to stabilize a ship in rough seas or to prevent capsizing. Another example might be intentionally grounding a ship to prevent it from sinking in deeper waters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the Common Good&lt;/strong&gt;: The sacrifice or expenditure must be made with the intention of preserving the vessel and the remaining cargo from a greater impending peril. This implies that the action wasn’t just beneficial for one party but for the overall venture. If the action taken preserves both the ship and the majority of its cargo, then it benefits all involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Average scenarios can arise in various situations, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Severe Weather Conditions&lt;/strong&gt;: Storms at sea can lead to decisions where cargo needs to be jettisoned to prevent a ship from being overwhelmed by the waves or capsizing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fire&lt;/strong&gt;: If there’s a fire onboard, and it becomes necessary to use the ship’s equipment or resources (which might damage some cargo) to fight the fire, this can lead to a General Average situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stranding&lt;/strong&gt;: If a ship is grounded or stranded and efforts to refloat it lead to damage or loss of cargo, this could trigger a General Average claim.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collision&lt;/strong&gt;: After a collision, if actions taken to save the ship and its cargo lead to a deliberate sacrifice of some parts of the vessel or its cargo, General Average may be invoked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other Emergencies&lt;/strong&gt;: Situations like machinery breakdowns leading to a ship seeking refuge at a port, thereby incurring additional expenses, can also come under the ambit of General Average if they are for the common safety.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s crucial to note that not all losses or damages at sea result in General Average. Only when a &lt;strong&gt;Voluntary Sacrifice&lt;/strong&gt; is made for the common good does the principle come into play. Once invoked, all parties involved (shipowners, cargo owners) share in the sacrifice or additional costs, based on the value of their interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Further Clarifications on General Average Occurrences&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;further-clarifications-on-general-average-occurrences&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#further-clarifications-on-general-average-occurrences&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When a potential General Average situation arises, there are several considerations and subsequent actions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial Assessment&lt;/strong&gt;: The ship’s captain, often with input from the crew and potentially advice from the shipowner and other stakeholders, makes a judgement call on the situation. The captain’s primary responsibility is the safety of the vessel, its crew, and cargo. Given the immediacy of many maritime perils, there often isn’t time for lengthy deliberations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication&lt;/strong&gt;: Once a decision has been made and action taken, the ship’s captain usually communicates with the shipowner, who in turn may notify insurance companies, cargo owners, and other relevant parties about the incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation&lt;/strong&gt;: Proper documentation of the events leading up to, during, and after the sacrifice is crucial. This might include logbook entries, photographs, testimonies from the crew, or any other relevant evidence. Such documentation helps in ascertaining the necessity and reasonableness of the action taken, which becomes crucial during the adjustment process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Port of Refuge&lt;/strong&gt;: In some General Average situations, a ship may need to divert to a nearby port (known as a port of refuge) for repairs, offloading damaged cargo, or other necessary actions. This can further complicate the scenario because of additional expenses like towage, port fees, storage, and potential salvage costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Salvage Costs&lt;/strong&gt;: If third-party salvors are involved in assisting the vessel (for example, by towing it to safety), their remuneration, known as salvage charges, could also be incorporated into General Average calculations. It’s worth noting that salvage charges are distinct from General Average but can be intertwined if the salvage operation involves sacrifices that qualify for General Average.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contestations and Disputes&lt;/strong&gt;: Given the high stakes and significant financial implications, General Average situations can sometimes lead to disputes. Parties might disagree on the necessity of the sacrifice, the valuation of the goods, or the apportionment of costs. In such cases, legal counsel might be sought, and disputes could be resolved in courts or through arbitration, depending on the terms stipulated in the bill of lading or charter party.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Implications&lt;/strong&gt;: The international nature of shipping means that a General Average incident can involve parties from multiple countries, each with its laws and regulations. The YORK-ANTWERP Rules, as mentioned earlier, aim to provide a standardized framework for handling these incidents, but local laws and regulations can still come into play.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the principle of General Average is straightforward, its application in real-world scenarios can be multifaceted and complex. Each incident is unique, shaped by the specifics of the situation, the parties involved, and the broader legal and commercial environment. For those involved in maritime trade and shipping, understanding General Average is not just about knowing the principle but also appreciating its nuances and intricacies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is charged in the event of a General Average (GA)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;who-is-charged-in-the-event-of-a-general-average-ga&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#who-is-charged-in-the-event-of-a-general-average-ga&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the event of a General Average, the financial burden is shared among all parties with a monetary interest in the voyage. This apportionment is based on the principle that all parties benefit from the voluntary sacrifice or extraordinary expense made for the common safety of the vessel and its cargo. Here’s a breakdown of who gets charged:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shipowner&lt;/strong&gt;: The shipowner is responsible for the value of the ship and any potential loss or damage it might incur during the voyage. If a part of the vessel is damaged or sacrificed for the common good, the shipowner shares in the General Average costs based on the ship’s value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cargo Owners&lt;/strong&gt;: Each cargo owner is charged based on the value of their cargo. If, for instance, some cargo is jettisoned to save the ship and the remaining cargo, then all cargo owners, not just the one whose cargo was jettisoned, will contribute to the General Average based on the proportionate value of their cargo onboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Charterer&lt;/strong&gt;: If the vessel is under a time charter, the charterer might also have some responsibilities under General Average, especially if they have an interest in the cargo or if the charter party agreement specifies such obligations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freight at Risk&lt;/strong&gt;: If freight (the charge for transporting goods) is at risk during the voyage, it can also be considered in the apportionment of the General Average. This means that the party entitled to the freight might need to contribute based on the freight value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of determining how much each party contributes is carried out by an “average adjuster,” a specialized professional who evaluates the circumstances of the General Average event, determines the value of the ship and the cargo at risk, calculates the total losses, and then apportions the contributions required from each party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the adjuster determines the amounts, the respective parties (or their insurers, if they have marine insurance that covers General Average contributions) are then charged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s essential to understand that even if a cargo owner’s goods were not damaged or sacrificed, they would still be required to contribute to the General Average if their cargo benefited from the sacrifice or expense made. This sharing of costs reinforces the principle of mutual risk and the collective venture of maritime voyages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is General Average Bond?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-is-general-average-bond&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-general-average-bond&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;General Average Bond&lt;/strong&gt; is a formal document that cargo owners are often required to provide after a General Average event has been declared. This bond serves as a cargo owner’s promise to pay their share of the General Average expenses and sacrifices once these are determined. Here’s a deeper look into the General Average Bond:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: The primary purpose of the General Average Bond is to ensure that the cargo owner commits to paying their proportional share of the General Average claim once it’s finalized. Given that the adjustment process can take a considerable amount of time (sometimes years), this bond acts as a guarantee that the cargo owner will not evade their responsibilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release of Cargo&lt;/strong&gt;: Before releasing the undamaged cargo at the port of destination, shipowners or their representatives will often require cargo owners to provide a General Average Bond. This ensures that, even though the final amount of the General Average claim has not been determined, there is a commitment from the cargo owner to cover their share once it’s established.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accompanied by Guarantees&lt;/strong&gt;: Along with the General Average Bond, cargo owners (or more commonly, their insurers) might also be asked to provide a &lt;strong&gt;General Average Guarantee&lt;/strong&gt;. This guarantee can be a bank guarantee, an insurance company guarantee, or occasionally a cash deposit. It’s an additional layer of assurance for the shipowner that the cargo owner or their insurer will meet their obligations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Settlement&lt;/strong&gt;: Once the average adjuster finalizes the calculations and the cargo owner’s contribution is determined, the cargo owner (or their insurer) is expected to pay the required amount. After the payment, the General Average Bond and any accompanying guarantee are discharged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insurance&lt;/strong&gt;: Most marine cargo insurance policies include coverage for General Average contributions. If a cargo owner has such insurance, the insurance company typically handles the provision of both the General Average Bond and the General Average Guarantee on the cargo owner’s behalf.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Average Bond is a commitment mechanism, ensuring that all parties involved will fulfill their obligations related to the General Average claim. Given the complexities and potential high costs associated with maritime incidents, such mechanisms are vital in protecting the interests of all stakeholders involved in the maritime venture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance and Implications of the General Average Bond&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;importance-and-implications-of-the-general-average-bond&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#importance-and-implications-of-the-general-average-bond&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Securing Interests&lt;/strong&gt;: From the shipowner’s perspective, the General Average Bond acts as a safety net. It ensures that even if the calculations related to General Average contributions take an extended period, there is a binding commitment from the cargo owner to settle their share once it’s determined.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal Binding&lt;/strong&gt;: The General Average Bond is not just a casual agreement. It’s a legally binding document, meaning that should a cargo owner fail to pay their determined share, the shipowner has legal grounds to pursue the matter in court.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interplay with Other Documents&lt;/strong&gt;: In some cases, especially where significant cargo values or complicated incidents are involved, there might be other related documents or agreements. For instance, if a salvage operation was required, separate salvage securities might be necessary in addition to the General Average Bond.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Variations&lt;/strong&gt;: Since shipping is an international industry, the approach to the General Average Bond can vary based on jurisdiction and local customs. However, principles derived from the YORK-ANTWERP Rules, which are often incorporated into shipping contracts, provide a common framework that many maritime stakeholders recognize.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenges for Uninsured Cargo Owners&lt;/strong&gt;: While those with marine cargo insurance can rely on their insurers to manage the General Average Bond process, uninsured cargo owners can find themselves in a more challenging situation. They must navigate the process themselves and ensure they provide the necessary securities to have their cargo released.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost Implications&lt;/strong&gt;: If a cargo owner cannot promptly provide a General Average Bond (and accompanying guarantee, if required), it might lead to delays in releasing their cargo. Such delays can result in additional costs, such as storage fees or demurrage charges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefit to the Maritime Community&lt;/strong&gt;: While the bond system might seem like a bureaucratic hurdle, it has long-term benefits for the maritime community. It instills a sense of shared responsibility and ensures that parties do not face undue financial burdens due to sacrifices or expenditures made for the common good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Average Bond is a critical component of the broader General Average principle. It embodies the commitment of all parties to uphold their responsibilities in the shared venture of maritime transport. Given the vast sums potentially at stake and the intricacies of maritime incidents, such mechanisms ensure fairness, accountability, and shared responsibility in the face of unpredictable sea-related challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Declaring General Average (GA) in Maritime Law&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;declaring-general-average-ga-in-maritime-law&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#declaring-general-average-ga-in-maritime-law&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Declaring General Average (GA)” in maritime law refers to the formal invocation of the ancient principle of General Average, which is rooted in the idea that all parties in a maritime venture should proportionally share extraordinary sacrifices made for the common good. When a General Average act occurs, it results in financial implications for all parties with a stake in the voyage, including shipowners, cargo owners, and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a breakdown of how General Average is declared and its implications in maritime law:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Precursor to a GA Declaration&lt;/strong&gt;: A GA act typically originates from an extraordinary event during a maritime voyage where a deliberate sacrifice or extraordinary expenditure is made to safeguard the ship and its cargo. Examples include jettisoning cargo to save the vessel or incurring extra costs due to unforeseen circumstances that benefit all stakeholders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain’s Decision&lt;/strong&gt;: The ship’s captain is often the first to identify and respond to a situation that might require a General Average act. While the captain’s primary responsibility is to ensure the safety of the ship, crew, and cargo, they also have the authority to make decisions that can later lead to a GA declaration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formal Declaration&lt;/strong&gt;: After the event, the shipowner or their representatives will formally declare General Average, usually based on advice from their legal counsel and after evaluating the captain’s report and other relevant details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appointment of an Average Adjuster&lt;/strong&gt;: Once GA is declared, an average adjuster is typically appointed. This professional is responsible for calculating the value of the losses, determining the contributions required from each stakeholder, and ensuring the proportional distribution of costs. The adjuster operates neutrally and is trusted by all involved parties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GA Securities&lt;/strong&gt;: Before cargo is released at the destination, those with an interest in it (usually cargo owners or consignees) are often required to furnish security, such as a General Average Bond and sometimes a cash deposit or insurer’s guarantee, assuring their commitment to pay any eventual contributions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Calculations&lt;/strong&gt;: The adjustment process can be intricate and time-consuming. It involves evaluating the circumstances of the GA act, tallying expenses, assessing the value of the ship and cargo, and then determining how much each party should contribute. Once finalized, parties are informed of their respective shares.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal Implications&lt;/strong&gt;: If a party refuses to pay their share, legal action can be taken to enforce payment. The legal basis for General Average is often found in the bill of lading, charter party agreements, and international conventions like the YORK-ANTWERP Rules, which provide standardized guidelines on how General Average should be adjusted and settled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insurance and GA&lt;/strong&gt;: Most marine insurance policies for cargo include provisions covering GA contributions. If insured, the cargo owner’s insurer typically handles the General Average process, from furnishing security to settling the finalized claim.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Declaring General Average is a structured process grounded in centuries-old maritime principles. It ensures fairness in apportioning extraordinary costs or sacrifices that arise from unforeseen events during sea voyages. Being familiar with this concept and its implications is crucial for anyone involved in maritime trade or shipping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to declare General Average (GA)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;how-to-declare-general-average-ga&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#how-to-declare-general-average-ga&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Declaring General Average (GA) is a formal procedure grounded in maritime law and practice. While the precise steps can vary depending on the jurisdiction, shipping line, and the specifics of the maritime incident, there is a general framework that is typically followed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify a GA Act&lt;/strong&gt;: The primary criteria for a GA declaration is that there has been a voluntary sacrifice or extraordinary expenditure made for the common safety of the vessel and its cargo. The ship’s captain, given the immediacy of many maritime perils, often makes this initial decision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Report the Incident&lt;/strong&gt;: The ship’s captain prepares a detailed report about the incident, which includes the nature of the peril, the action taken, and any potential damage to the ship or loss of cargo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notify Relevant Parties&lt;/strong&gt;: Once the incident has been identified as a potential GA act, the shipowner or their representatives will inform all relevant parties. This includes cargo owners, charterers (if applicable), and insurers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formal Declaration&lt;/strong&gt;: A formal GA declaration is made based on the shipowner’s evaluation of the captain’s report and consultation with legal counsel. This declaration is the official acknowledgment that the incident will be treated under the principles of General Average.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appoint an Average Adjuster&lt;/strong&gt;: A neutral average adjuster is appointed to handle the calculations and apportionment related to the GA act. Their role is to investigate the incident, determine the total value at risk (including the ship and cargo), evaluate the total amount of the loss, and calculate how much each party should contribute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provide GA Securities&lt;/strong&gt;: Before the undamaged cargo is released to its owners or consignees, they are typically required to provide a General Average Bond, which is a promise to pay their contribution once determined. Additionally, a cash deposit or a guarantee from an insurance company might also be requested as further security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calculation &amp;amp; Settlement&lt;/strong&gt;: The average adjuster, after thorough investigation and calculation, will determine the exact contributions required from each party. Once these are finalized, parties are informed and are expected to settle their respective amounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal Documentation&lt;/strong&gt;: The GA declaration, the average adjuster’s report, and other related documents serve as the legal basis for claims and contributions. These documents are crucial if there are disputes or if a party defaults on their obligation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insurance Claims&lt;/strong&gt;: If the cargo owners have marine insurance that covers GA, they will file a claim with their insurance company. The insurer typically handles the process of providing GA securities and settling the finalized contributions on behalf of the insured.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disputes &amp;amp; Arbitration&lt;/strong&gt;: If there’s disagreement over the declaration or the determined contributions, the issue might be resolved through legal channels or arbitration, depending on the terms set in the bill of lading or charter party agreement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s essential to note that while the GA principle is widely recognized, the process and specifics can vary based on local laws, shipping contracts, and the practices of individual shipping lines or companies. If you’re involved in a situation where GA might be declared, consulting with maritime legal experts is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How appoint Average Adjuster in General Average (GA)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;how-appoint-average-adjuster-in-general-average-ga&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#how-appoint-average-adjuster-in-general-average-ga&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appointing an Average Adjuster in the context of General Average (GA) is a crucial step to ensure that the apportionment of losses and expenses is done fairly and accurately. The Average Adjuster plays a central role in the GA process by impartially determining the contributions required from each involved party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a guide on how to appoint an Average Adjuster in General Average:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recognition of GA Incident&lt;/strong&gt;: The first step, even before the appointment of an Average Adjuster, is recognizing that a GA incident has occurred. The ship’s captain typically identifies this, and based on their report, the shipowner or their representative can decide to invoke the GA principle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seek Recommendations&lt;/strong&gt;: Especially if the shipowner or manager is unfamiliar with the ports or jurisdictions involved, they might seek recommendations for competent Average Adjusters from their insurance providers, P&amp;amp;I (Protection &amp;amp; Indemnity) clubs, or other maritime industry contacts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experience and Expertise&lt;/strong&gt;: It’s essential to choose an Average Adjuster with extensive experience and expertise in GA claims. Their knowledge of maritime law, cargo values, salvage operations, and the intricacies of the YORK-ANTWERP Rules or other applicable conventions is crucial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impartiality&lt;/strong&gt;: One of the primary qualities of an Average Adjuster is impartiality. They must serve all parties (shipowners, cargo owners, charterers, etc.) neutrally, ensuring a fair apportionment based on established rules and principles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formal Appointment&lt;/strong&gt;: Once an Average Adjuster is identified and vetted, they are formally appointed by the shipowner or their representative. This appointment is typically in writing, outlining the terms of engagement, responsibilities, and any fees or charges associated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provide Necessary Documentation&lt;/strong&gt;: The shipowner or their representatives must furnish the Average Adjuster with all necessary documentation and information, including the captain’s report, bills of lading, charter party agreements, and any other relevant documents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication with Stakeholders&lt;/strong&gt;: After the appointment, the Average Adjuster often communicates directly with all parties involved, informing them about the GA declaration, the adjustment process, and any securities or documentation required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conduct Investigation&lt;/strong&gt;: The Average Adjuster will begin a comprehensive investigation to determine the value of the ship, cargo, and any other interests. They will also assess the nature and value of the sacrifices and expenditures made in the GA incident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finalize and Communicate Adjustments&lt;/strong&gt;: Upon completion of the investigation and calculations, the Average Adjuster will compile a detailed adjustment report. This report specifies the contributions due from each party. The involved parties are then informed of their respective liabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintain Open Lines of Communication&lt;/strong&gt;: The Average Adjuster should be available to answer queries or provide clarifications throughout the process, ensuring transparency and understanding among all stakeholders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The appointment of an Average Adjuster in GA situations is fundamental to ensure a fair and orderly resolution of claims. Their role requires a blend of technical expertise, a deep understanding of maritime law and conventions, and impeccable integrity. When a GA situation arises, timely and careful selection of a qualified Average Adjuster is paramount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calculating General Average (GA) Example 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;calculating-general-average-ga-example-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#calculating-general-average-ga-example-1&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calculating General Average (GA) can be intricate, but to make it easier to understand, let’s go through a simplified hypothetical example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario&lt;/strong&gt;: Let’s assume a ship valued at $10 million is on a voyage carrying three separate consignments of cargo:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;scenario-lets-assume-a-ship-valued-at-10-million-is-on-a-voyage-carrying-three-separate-consignments-of-cargo&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#scenario-lets-assume-a-ship-valued-at-10-million-is-on-a-voyage-carrying-three-separate-consignments-of-cargo&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo A: Electronics worth $5 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo B: Furniture worth $3 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo C: Textiles worth $2 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the voyage, a fire breaks out in one of the cargo holds, threatening the entire ship and its cargo. To combat the fire and prevent the loss of the entire ship and cargo, the crew decides to jettison (throw overboard) Cargo A, the electronics worth $5 million. The action saves the ship and the remaining cargo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given these details, the total value at risk before the jettison was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship: $10 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo A: $5 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo B: $3 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo C: $2 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total: $20 million&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average Calculation&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;general-average-calculation&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#general-average-calculation&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Loss&lt;/strong&gt;: Cargo A worth $5 million was jettisoned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apportionment&lt;/strong&gt;: Each party contributes towards this loss based on the total value they had at risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calculations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship’s contribution = (Ship’s value / Total value) * Total loss = ($10 million / $20 million) * $5 million = $2.5 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo A’s contribution = (Cargo A’s value / Total value) * Total loss Note: Even though Cargo A was lost, it still needs to contribute towards its own jettison under GA rules. = ($5 million / $20 million) * $5 million = $1.25 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo B’s contribution = (Cargo B’s value / Total value) * Total loss = ($3 million / $20 million) * $5 million = $0.75 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo C’s contribution = (Cargo C’s value / Total value) * Total loss = ($2 million / $20 million) * $5 million = $0.5 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, based on the GA calculation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The shipowner pays $2.5 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo A pays $1.25 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo B pays $0.75 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo C pays $0.5 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, these contributions total the $5 million loss of Cargo A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that in real-life scenarios, additional factors like salvage costs, legal fees, and other expenses could come into play. Moreover, the actual calculations would typically be handled by an appointed average adjuster, who would provide a detailed and accurate apportionment. This example, however, provides a basic understanding of the GA principle and its workings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calculating General Average (GA) Example 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;calculating-general-average-ga-example-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#calculating-general-average-ga-example-2&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s another hypothetical example to further illustrate the concept of General Average (GA):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;scenario&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#scenario&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a ship valued at $20 million is carrying three separate consignments of cargo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo X: Cars worth $10 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo Y: Art pieces worth $5 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo Z: Grains worth $15 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While en route, the ship encounters a severe storm, which threatens to capsize it. To prevent this and stabilize the ship, a significant portion of Cargo Z (grains) worth $10 million has to be jettisoned. The ship and the remaining cargo are saved by this action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given these circumstances, the total value at risk before the jettison was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship: $20 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo X: $10 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo Y: $5 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo Z: $15 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total: $50 million&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average Calculation&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;general-average-calculation-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#general-average-calculation-1&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Loss&lt;/strong&gt;: Cargo Z worth $10 million was jettisoned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apportionment&lt;/strong&gt;: Each party contributes towards this loss based on the total value they had at risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calculations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship’s contribution = (Ship’s value / Total value) * Total loss = ($20 million / $50 million) * $10 million = $4 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo X’s contribution = (Cargo X’s value / Total value) * Total loss = ($10 million / $50 million) * $10 million = $2 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo Y’s contribution = (Cargo Y’s value / Total value) * Total loss = ($5 million / $50 million) * $10 million = $1 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo Z’s contribution = (Cargo Z’s value / Total value) * Total loss Note: Just as before, even though a part of Cargo Z was lost, it still contributes towards its own jettison under GA rules. = ($15 million / $50 million) * $10 million = $3 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, based on the GA calculation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The shipowner pays $4 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo X pays $2 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo Y pays $1 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo Z pays $3 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collectively, these contributions equate to the $10 million loss of the portion of Cargo Z.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Real-world GA scenarios might also account for various other costs, potential salvage operations, and fees, and the appointed average adjuster would handle the precise calculations, ensuring that each party’s contributions align with maritime conventions and agreements. However, this example serves to provide a fundamental grasp of the GA process and calculations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calculating General Average (GA) Example 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;calculating-general-average-ga-example-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#calculating-general-average-ga-example-3&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s delve into another example to further illustrate the intricacies of the General Average (GA) principle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;scenario-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#scenario-1&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a container ship, valued at $15 million, embarks on a voyage carrying three separate cargo consignments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo D: Pharmaceuticals worth $8 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo E: Steel machinery worth $12 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo F: Fresh produce worth $5 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the voyage, the ship’s engine fails. To save the ship and its cargo from being stranded at sea, a swift but expensive repair is made at the nearest port. This emergency repair costs $6 million and is deemed a GA expense since the repair was for the common benefit of all the cargoes and the ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given these details, the total value at risk before the expenditure was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship: $15 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo D: $8 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo E: $12 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo F: $5 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total: $40 million&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average Calculation&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;general-average-calculation-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#general-average-calculation-2&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Expenditure&lt;/strong&gt;: The emergency repair cost of $6 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apportionment&lt;/strong&gt;: Each party will contribute towards this expense based on the value they had at risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calculations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship’s contribution = (Ship’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($15 million / $40 million) * $6 million = $2.25 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo D’s contribution = (Cargo D’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($8 million / $40 million) * $6 million = $1.2 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo E’s contribution = (Cargo E’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($12 million / $40 million) * $6 million = $1.8 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo F’s contribution = (Cargo F’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($5 million / $40 million) * $6 million = $0.75 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the GA calculation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The shipowner pays $2.25 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo D pays $1.2 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo E pays $1.8 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo F pays $0.75 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sum of these contributions equals the $6 million emergency repair cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example differs from the previous ones as it highlights that GA doesn’t just apply to jettisoned cargo but also to extraordinary expenses incurred for the shared benefit of all stakeholders. It underscores the GA principle’s versatility in ensuring that all involved parties proportionally share the burden of unexpected sacrifices or expenditures during a maritime venture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calculating General Average (GA) Example 4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;calculating-general-average-ga-example-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#calculating-general-average-ga-example-4&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s explore yet another fictional scenario to further elucidate the workings of the General Average (GA) principle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;scenario-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#scenario-2&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A modern cruise ship, valued at $50 million, is journeying across the Atlantic. The ship also carries valuable artwork for an exhibition, valued at $20 million, and a shipment of luxury cars, valued at $30 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Midway, a severe water leak is detected in one of the compartments. If left unaddressed, it threatens the structural integrity of the ship and everything on board. A decision is made to dock at the nearest port, where emergency services and divers manage to seal the leak and pump out the water. This unplanned salvage operation costs $10 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given these circumstances, the total value at risk before the expense was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship: $50 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artwork: $20 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luxury Cars: $30 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total: $100 million&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average Calculation&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;general-average-calculation-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#general-average-calculation-3&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Expenditure&lt;/strong&gt;: The salvage operation costs $10 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apportionment&lt;/strong&gt;: Each party will contribute towards this expense based on the value they had at risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calculations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship’s contribution = (Ship’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($50 million / $100 million) * $10 million = $5 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artwork’s contribution = (Artwork’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($20 million / $100 million) * $10 million = $2 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luxury Cars’ contribution = (Luxury Cars’ value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($30 million / $100 million) * $10 million = $3 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the GA calculation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The shipowner pays $5 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of the artwork pays $2 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of the luxury cars pays $3 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The combined contributions total the $10 million spent on the emergency salvage operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This hypothetical situation underscores that General Average can apply in varied circumstances, not just in cases of jettisoned cargo. When extraordinary expenditures are made for the common benefit of all stakeholders, the GA principle ensures that such burdens are shared equitably amongst them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calculating General Average (GA) Example 5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;calculating-general-average-ga-example-5&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#calculating-general-average-ga-example-5&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s delve into another illustrative example of the General Average (GA) principle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;scenario-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#scenario-3&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suppose a bulk carrier ship, valued at $25 million, is transporting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo G: Coal worth $15 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo H: Timber worth $10 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo I: Crude oil worth $20 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the voyage, pirates threaten the ship. To deter the pirates and protect the ship and its cargo, the captain decides to hire a private security firm’s services, which deploys an emergency response team. The costs involved in deterring the pirates amount to $5 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the details, the total value at risk before incurring the security expense was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship: $25 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo G: $15 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo H: $10 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo I: $20 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total: $70 million&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average Calculation&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;general-average-calculation-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#general-average-calculation-4&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Expenditure&lt;/strong&gt;: The cost of the emergency security response is $5 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apportionment&lt;/strong&gt;: Each party contributes towards this cost based on the total value they had at risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calculations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship’s contribution = (Ship’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($25 million / $70 million) * $5 million = $1.7857 million (rounded to 4 decimal places)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo G’s contribution = (Cargo G’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($15 million / $70 million) * $5 million = $1.0714 million (rounded to 4 decimal places)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo H’s contribution = (Cargo H’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($10 million / $70 million) * $5 million = $0.7143 million (rounded to 4 decimal places)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo I’s contribution = (Cargo I’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($20 million / $70 million) * $5 million = $1.4286 million (rounded to 4 decimal places)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the GA calculation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The shipowner contributes $1.7857 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo G contributes $1.0714 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo H contributes $0.7143 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo I contributes $1.4286 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, these contributions cover the $5 million expenditure for the emergency security response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example emphasizes that General Average isn’t limited to physical sacrifices or damages. Extraordinary expenses, incurred to protect the shared interest of all involved parties, also fall under the GA principle, ensuring the equitable distribution of such unexpected costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calculating General Average (GA) Example 6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;calculating-general-average-ga-example-6&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#calculating-general-average-ga-example-6&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s explore a sixth illustrative example to deepen the understanding of the General Average (GA) principle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine an oil tanker, valued at $40 million, carries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo J: Refined petrol worth $30 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo K: Diesel worth $20 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Midway through the journey, a fire breaks out in the engine room. To extinguish the fire and prevent a catastrophic explosion that could destroy the entire ship and its cargo, expensive firefighting chemicals are used. This firefighting operation, including the costs of chemicals and subsequent damages to machinery, sums up to $8 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given this, the total value at risk before the firefighting costs was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship: $40 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo J: $30 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo K: $20 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total: $90 million&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average Calculation&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;general-average-calculation-5&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#general-average-calculation-5&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Expenditure&lt;/strong&gt;: The firefighting operation and subsequent damage repair cost $8 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apportionment&lt;/strong&gt;: Each party will contribute towards this expense based on the value they had at risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calculations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship’s contribution = (Ship’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($40 million / $90 million) * $8 million = $3.5556 million (rounded to 4 decimal places)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo J’s contribution = (Cargo J’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($30 million / $90 million) * $8 million = $2.6667 million (rounded to 4 decimal places)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo K’s contribution = (Cargo K’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($20 million / $90 million) * $8 million = $1.7778 million (rounded to 4 decimal places)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the GA calculation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The shipowner pays $3.5556 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo J pays $2.6667 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo K pays $1.7778 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The combined contributions meet the $8 million cost incurred from the firefighting operation and subsequent damages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example showcases how unexpected incidents at sea that lead to extraordinary expenditures, necessary for the common good of both the vessel and the cargo, fall under the GA principle. All stakeholders involved proportionally share the costs of such unforeseen events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calculating General Average (GA) Example 7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;calculating-general-average-ga-example-7&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#calculating-general-average-ga-example-7&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s explore a seventh example to continue our understanding of the General Average (GA) principle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider a research vessel, valued at $20 million, on a special scientific expedition. On board, it carries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo L: Specialized scientific equipment worth $10 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo M: A collection of rare marine samples worth $5 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo N: Solar panels and batteries meant for a remote research base, worth $15 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to a sudden and severe storm, the vessel risks capsizing. To stabilize the ship, they have to release some of the heavy scientific equipment into the ocean. The value of jettisoned equipment amounts to $4 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the situation, the total value at risk before the jettison was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship: $20 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo L (before jettison): $10 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo M: $5 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo N: $15 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total: $50 million&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average Calculation&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;general-average-calculation-6&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#general-average-calculation-6&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Expenditure&lt;/strong&gt;: The jettisoned equipment is valued at $4 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apportionment&lt;/strong&gt;: Each party will contribute towards this loss based on the value they had at risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calculations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship’s contribution = (Ship’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($20 million / $50 million) * $4 million = $1.6 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo L’s contribution (considering the original value before jettison) = (Cargo L’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($10 million / $50 million) * $4 million = $0.8 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo M’s contribution = (Cargo M’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($5 million / $50 million) * $4 million = $0.4 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo N’s contribution = (Cargo N’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($15 million / $50 million) * $4 million = $1.2 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the GA calculation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The shipowner contributes $1.6 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo L contributes $0.8 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo M contributes $0.4 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo N contributes $1.2 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, these contributions compensate for the $4 million worth of equipment that was jettisoned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example sheds light on a situation where a tangible sacrifice (jettison) is made for the common good, highlighting that the GA principle ensures such losses are fairly distributed amongst all parties based on their stake in the entire venture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calculating General Average (GA) Example 8&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;calculating-general-average-ga-example-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#calculating-general-average-ga-example-8&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s delve into an eighth illustrative example to further understand the General Average (GA) principle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a state-of-the-art container ship, valued at $100 million, transporting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo O: Electronics (e.g., smartphones, laptops) worth $60 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo P: Pharmaceuticals (medicines and vaccines) worth $40 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo Q: Designer clothing and accessories worth $20 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While navigating through a coral reef, the ship gets stuck. To refloat the ship without causing significant damage to the environment or further damage to the vessel, tugboats and specialized equipment are required. The entire operation to safely dislodge the ship costs $12 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the refloating operation, the total value at risk was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship: $100 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo O: $60 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo P: $40 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo Q: $20 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total: $220 million&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average Calculation&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;general-average-calculation-7&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#general-average-calculation-7&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Expenditure&lt;/strong&gt;: The cost of the refloating operation is $12 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apportionment&lt;/strong&gt;: Each party contributes towards this expense based on the value they had at risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calculations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship’s contribution = (Ship’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($100 million / $220 million) * $12 million = $5.4545 million (rounded to 4 decimal places)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo O’s contribution = (Cargo O’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($60 million / $220 million) * $12 million = $3.2727 million (rounded to 4 decimal places)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo P’s contribution = (Cargo P’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($40 million / $220 million) * $12 million = $2.1818 million (rounded to 4 decimal places)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo Q’s contribution = (Cargo Q’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($20 million / $220 million) * $12 million = $1.0909 million (rounded to 4 decimal places)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the GA calculation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The shipowner contributes $5.4545 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo O contributes $3.2727 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo P contributes $2.1818 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owner of Cargo Q contributes $1.0909 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, these contributions equate to the $12 million expended during the refloating operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example underscores that General Average encompasses a wide array of unforeseen incidents and expenditures, and ensures the proportional sharing of such extraordinary expenses among all stakeholders involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calculating General Average (GA) Example 9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;calculating-general-average-ga-example-9&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#calculating-general-average-ga-example-9&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s examine a ninth illustrative example to further illustrate the General Average (GA) principle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Envision a cruise ship, valued at $150 million, which besides carrying passengers also transports:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo R: Artwork for an exhibition, worth $30 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo S: A consignment of premium wines, worth $15 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo T: High-end automobiles for an international car show, worth $45 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the journey, there’s a severe engine malfunction which necessitates an immediate stop at the nearest port for repairs. At the port, while the repairs are conducted, passengers need to be accommodated in hotels, and all cargoes need special warehousing to maintain their condition. The total unforeseen expenditure for repairs, passenger accommodation, and cargo warehousing is $20 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the scenario, the total value at risk before the unplanned expenditures was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship: $150 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo R: $30 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo S: $15 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo T: $45 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total: $240 million&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average Calculation&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;general-average-calculation-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#general-average-calculation-8&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Expenditure&lt;/strong&gt;: The combined cost for the repairs, accommodations, and warehousing is $20 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apportionment&lt;/strong&gt;: Each party contributes towards this cost based on the value they had at risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calculations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship’s contribution = (Ship’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($150 million / $240 million) * $20 million = $12.5 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo R’s contribution = (Cargo R’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($30 million / $240 million) * $20 million = $2.5 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo S’s contribution = (Cargo S’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($15 million / $240 million) * $20 million = $1.25 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo T’s contribution = (Cargo T’s value / Total value) * Total expenditure = ($45 million / $240 million) * $20 million = $3.75 million&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the GA calculation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cruise ship operator pays $12.5 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The consignor of Cargo R contributes $2.5 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The consignor of Cargo S contributes $1.25 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The consignor of Cargo T contributes $3.75 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collectively, these contributions compensate for the $20 million unexpected costs incurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example demonstrates how the GA principle operates when a maritime journey faces unexpected challenges that don’t necessarily involve weather disasters or jettisoning cargo, but still lead to significant shared costs. The principle ensures that all stakeholders involved contribute their fair share to alleviate the common burden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites for a General Average (GA) and The York Antwerp Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;prerequisites-for-a-general-average-ga-and-the-york-antwerp-rules&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#prerequisites-for-a-general-average-ga-and-the-york-antwerp-rules&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the prerequisites for a General Average (GA) and the significance of the York-Antwerp Rules is essential in the maritime industry. Let’s delve into these concepts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites for a General Average:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;prerequisites-for-a-general-average&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#prerequisites-for-a-general-average&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common Maritime Adventure&lt;/strong&gt;: There must be a common maritime venture, which typically means that the ship and the cargo (or at least some portion of the cargo) are at risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extraordinary Sacrifice or Expenditure&lt;/strong&gt;: A voluntary sacrifice must be made, or an extraordinary expenditure incurred, which directly benefits the common interest of the parties involved in the venture. This is not the same as regular expenses of a voyage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intentional Act&lt;/strong&gt;: The act resulting in the sacrifice or extraordinary expense must be intentional and not merely accidental. For example, jettisoning cargo to lighten a ship is intentional, whereas accidental damage from rough seas would not qualify.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Successful Preservation&lt;/strong&gt;: The sacrifice or expenditure must be successful, at least in part, in preserving the maritime property at risk. If the actions taken do not result in any preservation, GA may not apply.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The York-Antwerp Rules:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;the-york-antwerp-rules&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-york-antwerp-rules&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The York-Antwerp Rules are a set of guidelines developed to provide standardized rules for determining what constitutes a GA act and how contributions should be calculated. They have been adopted by many countries and provide a uniform framework to determine and settle GA claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key points of the York-Antwerp Rules:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;key-points-of-the-york-antwerp-rules&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#key-points-of-the-york-antwerp-rules&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uniformity&lt;/strong&gt;: They establish a standard system for the adjustment of general average, ensuring consistency and fairness in the treatment of GA incidents across different jurisdictions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GA Act Definition&lt;/strong&gt;: The rules define what can be considered a GA act and what costs can be claimed under GA. They also detail the documentation required for claims.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adjustment&lt;/strong&gt;: They lay out the process for adjusting general average contributions. An average adjuster, a specialized professional, often does this work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Absorption Clauses&lt;/strong&gt;: One of the notable changes in the more recent versions of the York-Antwerp Rules relates to absorption clauses. These clauses state that under a certain threshold, carriers absorb the general average contributions, ensuring that small claims don’t get passed onto cargo interests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Bar&lt;/strong&gt;: There’s a time limitation for presenting a claim under the York-Antwerp Rules. Claimants must present their claims within a certain time frame to ensure timely and efficient resolution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application and acceptance of the York-Antwerp Rules depend on the contract of carriage. Parties might agree in their contract to be governed by these rules, ensuring that in the event of a GA act, the rules will provide the guiding principles for the adjustment process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Average is a fundamental principle in maritime law, aiming to fairly distribute extraordinary losses among all parties involved in a maritime adventure. The York-Antwerp Rules, meanwhile, provide the needed framework to ensure this distribution is done systematically and fairly across different jurisdictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The York-Antwerp Rules 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;the-york-antwerp-rules-2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-york-antwerp-rules-2016&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The York-Antwerp Rules have undergone several revisions since their inception in the 19th century to better address the complexities of modern maritime operations. The 2016 version of the York-Antwerp Rules is one of the more recent iterations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;York-Antwerp Rules 2016&lt;/strong&gt; were adopted at the Comité Maritime International (CMI) Conference held in New York in May 2016. This version sought to bring clarity, modernize terms, and address challenges presented by prior versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some highlights and key changes of the 2016 Rules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule Paramount&lt;/strong&gt;: This rule states that the Rules apply when specifically incorporated into a contract, emphasizing the contractual nature of the rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Absorption Deductible&lt;/strong&gt;: Rule C was revised to introduce the concept of an absorption deductible. Carriers can contractually agree to absorb amounts below this deductible, which means small claims might not get passed on to cargo interests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treatment of Salvage&lt;/strong&gt;: One significant change in the 2016 rules is the treatment of salvage. Under Rule VI, if salvage is performed under a “No Cure – No Pay” basis, and if the salvors recover their reward in full, the costs of the salvage operation shall not be allowed as general average. This change addressed concerns that the previous rules overly favored salvors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adjustment of General Average&lt;/strong&gt;: Rule A emphasizes that the objective of the rules is to ensure that property is made to contribute based on its actual value at the end of the voyage, with more specific guidelines on the assessment of this value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temporary Repairs&lt;/strong&gt;: Rule XIV was revised to allow for temporary repairs at a port of refuge to be claimable in general average even if permanent repairs are not carried out at the final port of destination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environmental Fund&lt;/strong&gt;: Rule XI(d) was introduced, which concerns the establishment and operation of an environmental fund when there’s an escape or threat of escape of oil or other pollutants. This reflects growing environmental concerns in the maritime industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commission and Interest&lt;/strong&gt;: Rule XXI was revised to reduce the rate of interest applied to outstanding GA contributions. The 2016 rules lowered the interest rate compared to the 2004 version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Bar&lt;/strong&gt;: Rule XXIII clarifies that actions for contributions to general average shall be time-barred after one year, but parties have the ability to extend this if they so agree.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2016 version was crafted after considerable deliberation, and while they did not radically change the previous principles, they offered clarifications and updated provisions to better reflect the current challenges and realities of maritime operations. As with any version of the York-Antwerp Rules, their application is based on being contractually agreed upon by the parties involved in the maritime venture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is GA in marine insurance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-is-ga-in-marine-insurance&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-ga-in-marine-insurance&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of marine insurance, “GA” refers to “General Average.” General Average is a principle of maritime law wherein all stakeholders in a sea voyage (shipowners, cargo owners, etc.) proportionally share certain losses incurred during the voyage due to extraordinary sacrifices or expenditures made to preserve the voyage from an imminent peril.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a breakdown of how GA operates within marine insurance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average Declaration&lt;/strong&gt;: If an incident occurs during a voyage that necessitates a voluntary sacrifice (like jettisoning some cargo) or incurs an extraordinary expense (like tugboat assistance), and this action preserves the remaining property, a General Average act might be declared by the shipowner or captain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Role of Marine Insurance&lt;/strong&gt;: When a GA act is declared, cargo owners may be required to contribute towards the loss, even if their specific cargo wasn’t damaged or sacrificed. If the cargo owner has marine insurance, their insurance policy will typically cover their portion of the General Average contribution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Average Adjusters&lt;/strong&gt;: After a GA act, average adjusters are appointed to assess the incident, verify the amounts involved, and determine the contributions required from each party. They ensure that the distribution of costs adheres to the principles of General Average.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;York-Antwerp Rules&lt;/strong&gt;: Many marine insurance policies and bills of lading stipulate that any General Average adjustments should be made in accordance with the York-Antwerp Rules. These rules provide standardized guidelines for determining and settling GA claims.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average Bond&lt;/strong&gt;: Before cargo is released to the owner after a GA incident, they may be required to provide security, often in the form of a General Average Bond. If they have marine insurance, their insurer will often provide this bond on their behalf.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GA Guarantee&lt;/strong&gt;: Insurance companies can also issue a GA guarantee. This serves as a promise by the insurer to cover the insured party’s contribution to the GA, allowing the cargo to be released without an immediate payment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the framework of marine insurance, General Average introduces an element of shared risk. The rationale behind this is the spirit of shared venture; all parties involved in the maritime venture share the risks and, thus, should also share the extraordinary costs or losses that might arise during the voyage. Having marine insurance ensures that if a shipper or cargo owner is asked to contribute to a GA loss, they are financially protected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is General Average Claim in marine insurance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-is-general-average-claim-in-marine-insurance&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-general-average-claim-in-marine-insurance&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In marine insurance, a General Average (GA) claim arises when an extraordinary sacrifice or expenditure is intentionally and reasonably made or incurred for the common safety of a maritime adventure to preserve the property involved from a common peril.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s delve into the specifics of a General Average claim in marine insurance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initiation of a GA Claim&lt;/strong&gt;: A GA claim is typically initiated when an event occurs during a voyage that necessitates an intentional extraordinary sacrifice or expenditure to save the vessel and its cargo from an imminent danger. Examples include jettisoning part of the cargo to stabilize a ship in rough seas or incurring significant costs to tug a grounded vessel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Declaration&lt;/strong&gt;: After such an event, the shipowner or captain can declare a General Average. This declaration signifies that the costs or losses arising from the sacrifice or expenditure will be shared among all the parties involved in the maritime venture – the shipowner and all cargo owners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Average Adjusters&lt;/strong&gt;: Once GA is declared, average adjusters are appointed. Their role is to assess the situation, determine the value of the loss or expenditure, and then calculate how much each party (ship and cargo owners) should contribute based on the value of their interest in the venture. They’ll prepare a detailed adjustment outlining each party’s contribution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Claiming from Marine Insurance&lt;/strong&gt;: If a cargo owner has marine insurance, they can submit their GA contribution as a claim to their insurer. The insurance company will then evaluate the claim, and if valid, will cover the cost of the cargo owner’s GA contribution. This ensures that individual cargo owners aren’t financially burdened by unforeseen events during the voyage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average Bond &amp;amp; Guarantee&lt;/strong&gt;: Before releasing the cargo, the shipowner may require cargo owners to provide a GA bond as a security against their GA contribution. Additionally, if the cargo owner has marine insurance, their insurer can provide a GA guarantee on their behalf, promising to cover the GA contribution when the adjustment is finalized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finalization of Claims&lt;/strong&gt;: The GA adjustment process can be lengthy, sometimes taking years, especially for complex cases. Once the average adjuster finalizes the adjustments, and the exact contributions are determined, parties are required to pay their share. If a cargo owner’s insurer provided a GA guarantee, the insurer would now pay the finalized amount.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Average claim in marine insurance represents a mechanism through which the financial burden of an extraordinary event, intended to preserve the maritime venture from peril, is equitably distributed among all stakeholders. The principle underscores the shared nature of maritime risks, and marine insurance provides cargo owners with protection against potential GA contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is General Average Loss in marine insurance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-is-general-average-loss-in-marine-insurance&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-general-average-loss-in-marine-insurance&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In marine insurance, a General Average (GA) loss refers to a loss that arises due to an extraordinary sacrifice or expenditure made with the intention to safeguard the entirety of a maritime adventure (i.e., both the vessel and its cargo) from an imminent peril.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a detailed look at General Average Loss:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nature of the Loss&lt;/strong&gt;: A GA loss is not a typical loss or damage that may occur during a voyage, like damages from rough seas or routine machinery breakdown. Instead, it originates from a deliberate action taken to prevent a greater peril or disaster. This action must be above and beyond the regular duties of the crew or the ordinary course of a voyage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examples of GA Loss&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jettisoning Cargo&lt;/strong&gt;: If a ship is in danger of capsizing during a storm, and some of the cargo is thrown overboard (jettisoned) to stabilize the vessel, this sacrificed cargo represents a GA loss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tug Assistance&lt;/strong&gt;: If a ship runs aground and needs tugboats to pull it to safety, the expenses incurred for the tugs can be considered a GA loss if the action was to preserve the entire venture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shared Responsibility&lt;/strong&gt;: The principle behind General Average is that the maritime adventure is a joint venture between the shipowner and the cargo owners. Therefore, when a GA loss occurs, the resulting financial burden is shared proportionally among all parties based on the value of their respective interests (i.e., the value of the ship and the value of the cargo).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marine Insurance’s Role&lt;/strong&gt;: If a cargo owner has marine insurance coverage that includes GA provisions, they can claim their proportionate share of the GA loss from their insurance company. The insurer then compensates the insured based on the policy’s terms, ensuring that the cargo owner isn’t unduly burdened financially.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Average Adjusters&lt;/strong&gt;: After a GA loss is declared, average adjusters are typically appointed to assess the situation, calculate the total value of the loss, and determine each party’s contribution based on the value of their stake in the venture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Average Loss in marine insurance pertains to a loss resulting from a voluntary and extraordinary action taken during a voyage to preserve the whole maritime adventure from a greater peril. This loss is then equitably distributed among all the stakeholders involved, and marine insurance serves to protect these stakeholders, especially cargo owners, from the financial implications of such an event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is insurance for General Average (GA)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-is-insurance-for-general-average-ga&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-insurance-for-general-average-ga&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insurance for General Average is essentially a provision within marine insurance policies that covers the insured’s contribution to a General Average loss. In the maritime world, General Average refers to the ancient principle where all parties involved in a maritime voyage (shipowners and cargo owners) share proportionally in the losses resulting from a voluntary sacrifice made to save the voyage from an imminent peril.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s delve into the specifics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average Principle&lt;/strong&gt;: In situations where an extraordinary sacrifice or expenditure is intentionally made to preserve the ship and its cargo from a major peril, a General Average is declared. The resulting losses or expenses are then shared among all stakeholders, based on the value of their interests (i.e., the ship’s value and cargo value).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coverage in Marine Insurance&lt;/strong&gt;: Marine insurance policies usually include provisions to cover General Average contributions. This means that if a cargo owner’s goods are not damaged but a General Average act occurs (like jettisoning some cargo to save the ship), they might still be liable for a portion of the loss. Their marine insurance would then step in to cover this liability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average Clause&lt;/strong&gt;: Within a marine insurance policy, there will typically be a General Average clause that details the conditions under which the insurance company will pay for a General Average loss. It might stipulate, for instance, that the voyage must be conducted between specific ports or that the General Average adjustment should be in accordance with the York-Antwerp Rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average Bond and Guarantee&lt;/strong&gt;: After a General Average act, before the cargo is released to its owner, the shipowner might require security in the form of a General Average bond. Additionally, if the cargo owner has marine insurance, their insurer may provide a General Average guarantee on their behalf, committing to cover the insured’s General Average contribution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance&lt;/strong&gt;: Insurance for General Average is crucial because, in maritime voyages, unexpected events can lead to substantial losses. By having this insurance, cargo owners protect themselves from the financial repercussions of such events, even when their cargo isn’t directly affected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insurance for General Average is a fundamental aspect of marine insurance policies. It ensures that, in the event of a General Average act, cargo owners (and shipowners, if they’re the insured party) are protected from the potential financial burdens that arise from the shared losses or expenses of the maritime venture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to get insurance for General Average (GA)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;how-to-get-insurance-for-general-average-ga&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#how-to-get-insurance-for-general-average-ga&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obtaining insurance for General Average (GA) is typically done through procuring a comprehensive marine insurance policy. Here’s a step-by-step guide on how to get insurance for GA:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assess Your Needs&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate the type of cargo you’re shipping, its value, and the routes or regions you’ll be shipping through. These factors can affect the type and extent of coverage you might need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider any specific risks associated with the cargo, voyage, or shipping routes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research Insurance Providers&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for insurance companies or brokers that specialize in marine insurance. They’ll have a better understanding of the intricacies of GA and related matters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read reviews or ask peers in the industry for recommendations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact Insurance Brokers or Agents&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A broker or agent can guide you through the different policies available, helping you find one that provides GA coverage tailored to your needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They’ll explain the terms, conditions, and any exclusions that may apply.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Review Policy Terms&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure that the policy explicitly covers General Average contributions. This is standard in most marine cargo insurance policies, but it’s essential to confirm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarize yourself with any conditions, such as compliance with the York-Antwerp Rules or specific documentation requirements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understand the Premium Calculation&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Premiums can be influenced by the cargo value, shipping routes, type of cargo, and other risk factors. It’s important to understand how your premium is calculated to ensure you’re getting a fair rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provide Necessary Documentation&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The insurer may require documentation about the cargo, its value, the shipping route, and other relevant details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure all documentation is accurate to avoid potential complications in case of a claim.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finalize and Purchase the Policy&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once you’re satisfied with the terms and premium, finalize the policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure to retain a copy of the policy document, and familiarize yourself with the claims process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay Updated&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marine insurance, like all insurance types, might have renewals. Ensure you renew your policy on time and update it as necessary if there are changes in your shipping patterns, cargo types, or values.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay informed about any changes in maritime laws or regulations that might affect GA and related insurance matters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Case of a General Average Event&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a GA event occurs, notify your insurer immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide all required documentation and cooperate fully with average adjusters or other appointed parties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your insurer will guide you through the claims process and, if you’re covered, will handle your GA contribution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s crucial to maintain open communication with your insurer and ensure you understand the terms and conditions of your policy. This way, you’re well-prepared in the event of a GA declaration or any other marine-related incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is General Average (GA) and Particular Average (PA) in shipping?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-is-general-average-ga-and-particular-average-pa-in-shipping&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-general-average-ga-and-particular-average-pa-in-shipping&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Average (GA) and Particular Average (PA) are concepts in shipping and marine insurance that address the distribution of loss experienced during maritime adventures. Both terms are essential in determining liability and indemnification in maritime incidents. Here’s a breakdown of both:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. General Average (GA):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;1-general-average-ga&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#1-general-average-ga&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition&lt;/strong&gt;: GA is a principle in maritime law whereby all parties in a sea venture proportionally share any losses resulting from a voluntary and intentional sacrifice of part of the ship or cargo to save the whole voyage from an imminent peril.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Suppose a ship encounters a severe storm, and to stabilize the vessel, some cargo is intentionally thrown overboard (jettisoned). Although only one or a few cargo owners suffer a direct loss, the principle of GA spreads the financial burden of that loss among all the cargo owners and the shipowner, proportional to their respective interests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Declaration&lt;/strong&gt;: In events leading to GA, the shipowner or captain declares a General Average. Subsequently, an average adjuster is typically appointed to calculate and apportion the contributions from each party.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Particular Average (PA):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;2-particular-average-pa&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#2-particular-average-pa&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition&lt;/strong&gt;: PA refers to a partial loss of the ship or cargo that is borne solely by the owner of the damaged property and not shared with other parties. This loss typically arises from the everyday risks of seafaring and is not associated with a deliberate sacrifice to save the venture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: If a shipment of electronics gets damaged due to seawater ingress, but no extraordinary event or sacrifice took place to prevent a bigger disaster, this loss is considered a Particular Average. The loss is borne entirely by the owner of the damaged goods, or if they have marine insurance, by their insurer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marine Insurance Role&lt;/strong&gt;: In the context of marine insurance, if an insured cargo suffers a Particular Average loss, the cargo owner can file a claim with their insurer to cover the damage or loss, as per the terms of their policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While both General Average and Particular Average address losses incurred during maritime voyages, the key difference lies in how these losses are treated. GA involves a shared, proportionate responsibility among all involved parties due to a deliberate sacrifice for the common good, whereas PA concerns individual losses borne solely by the owner of the damaged property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between General Average (GA) and Particular Average (PA)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-is-the-difference-between-general-average-ga-and-particular-average-pa&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-the-difference-between-general-average-ga-and-particular-average-pa&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Average (GA) and Particular Average (PA) are both concepts related to losses incurred during maritime voyages, but they differ in terms of their causes, implications, and how they are borne by the parties involved. Here’s a comparison highlighting their differences:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 Cause and Nature of Loss:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;1-cause-and-nature-of-loss&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#1-cause-and-nature-of-loss&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average (GA)&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cause&lt;/strong&gt;: Arises due to a voluntary and deliberate act taken to preserve the entire maritime adventure (both the vessel and its cargo) from an imminent and substantial peril.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nature of Loss&lt;/strong&gt;: The loss results from a sacrifice made for the greater good of the entire voyage. This could be jettisoning cargo to stabilize a ship during a storm or incurring extraordinary expenses like towing to protect the vessel and cargo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Particular Average (PA)&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cause&lt;/strong&gt;: Arises from the usual perils and dangers of the sea or other ordinary incidents of the voyage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nature of Loss&lt;/strong&gt;: The loss is accidental and not the result of a deliberate act to save the whole venture. It’s essentially a partial loss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 Distribution of Liability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;2-distribution-of-liability&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#2-distribution-of-liability&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average (GA)&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The resulting financial burden of the loss or expenditure is spread among all stakeholders involved in the maritime venture. This means both shipowners and cargo owners share in the financial responsibility, each contributing proportionally based on the value of their interests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Particular Average (PA)&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The financial burden of the loss falls solely on the owner of the damaged or lost property. There is no spreading of the cost among other parties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 Insurance Implication:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;3-insurance-implication&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#3-insurance-implication&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average (GA)&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a GA is declared, cargo owners may be required to provide a General Average bond and possibly a cash deposit before their goods are released. If they have marine insurance, their insurer would typically cover their share of the GA expenditure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Particular Average (PA)&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a cargo owner has marine insurance that covers PA losses, they can claim compensation for their damaged or lost goods. The insurer compensates based on the terms of the policy, usually after considering depreciation, deductibles, and other relevant factors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4 Examples:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;4-examples&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#4-examples&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average (GA)&lt;/strong&gt;: If a ship is at risk of sinking in a storm and some cargo is thrown overboard to save the vessel, this is a GA act. All parties involved in the maritime venture share the cost of the jettisoned cargo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Particular Average (PA)&lt;/strong&gt;: If a few containers of cargo get wet and damaged due to a minor water leak in the ship’s hold, without any broader peril to the entire voyage, this loss is a PA. Only the owners of the damaged cargo bear the loss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5 Declaration and Adjustments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;5-declaration-and-adjustments&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#5-declaration-and-adjustments&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average (GA)&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When an event that could lead to a GA declaration occurs, it’s typically the shipowner or captain who declares it. Following such a declaration, an average adjuster is often appointed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The role of the average adjuster is crucial. They will gather all the pertinent information, determine the value of the sacrificed goods, and apportion the shared loss among the ship and cargo owners based on their respective interests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Particular Average (PA)&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PA doesn’t necessitate a formal declaration like GA. Instead, the cargo owner or shipowner (depending on where the loss occurs) will usually document the loss, gather evidence, and, if insured, contact their insurance company to initiate the claims process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 Legal and Contractual Implications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;6-legal-and-contractual-implications&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#6-legal-and-contractual-implications&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average (GA)&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GA principles are deeply rooted in maritime law and have been in practice for centuries. Many international shipping contracts and bills of lading have clauses that address the GA principle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The York-Antwerp Rules, which provide a standardized set of guidelines for GA declarations and adjustments, are widely recognized and used in the industry to ensure consistency and fairness in GA claims.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Particular Average (PA)&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PA claims are typically governed by the terms of the marine insurance policy, the shipping contract, and any applicable laws or conventions of the jurisdictions involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlike GA, there isn’t a universally recognized set of rules governing PA. Each claim is handled based on its individual merits and the specifics of the contractual and insurance agreements in place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Financial Implications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;7-financial-implications&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#7-financial-implications&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Average (GA)&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since GA losses are distributed among various parties, individual financial burdens might be less than if one party had to bear the entire loss. However, unforeseen GA costs can be a surprise to cargo owners unaware of their potential liabilities in such events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Particular Average (PA)&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PA losses can be a financial burden to the affected party, especially if they are significant and the owner is uninsured. It underscores the importance of comprehensive marine insurance coverage for cargo and ships alike.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the differences between GA and PA is pivotal for anyone involved in maritime commerce. It informs decision-making on insurance, risk management, and contractual commitments, ensuring that stakeholders are adequately prepared for the financial and procedural challenges that might arise during sea voyages. While both GA and PA deal with maritime losses, the key difference lies in the nature and distribution of the loss. GA involves shared responsibility due to a deliberate act for the overall good, whereas PA pertains to individual losses not shared with other parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;**What happens in case of General Average (GA)? **&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-happens-in-case-of-general-average-ga&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-happens-in-case-of-general-average-ga&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the maritime world, when a General Average (GA) event occurs, it sets into motion a series of actions and processes designed to ensure fairness and proportionality in sharing the losses or expenses that arise from the event. Here’s a step-by-step breakdown of what happens in the case of a GA:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Incident Occurs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;1-incident-occurs&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#1-incident-occurs&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A peril threatens the safety of the ship and its cargo, leading the ship’s master or crew to take deliberate action, like jettisoning cargo, to preserve the voyage. This voluntary sacrifice sets the stage for a potential GA declaration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Declaration of General Average:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;2-declaration-of-general-average&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#2-declaration-of-general-average&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ship’s master or the shipowner declares a GA. This is a formal announcement that certain actions taken were for the common good and safety of the voyage, and thus the associated costs or losses should be shared among all parties involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Appointment of Average Adjuster:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;3-appointment-of-average-adjuster&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#3-appointment-of-average-adjuster&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An average adjuster, who is a specialized expert in the field of marine insurance and GA claims, is typically appointed to handle the GA adjustments. This individual or firm evaluates the event, determines the total cost or loss, and calculates how it should be apportioned among the various stakeholders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Submission of General Average Bonds:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;4-submission-of-general-average-bonds&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#4-submission-of-general-average-bonds&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before cargo can be released to its owners at the port of destination, those owners (or their insurers) are usually required to provide a General Average Bond. This bond is a guarantee that they will pay their contribution towards the GA once it is determined. Sometimes, a cash deposit might also be required as security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Adjustment Process:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;5-adjustment-process&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#5-adjustment-process&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The average adjuster gathers all necessary information, such as ship’s logs, invoices, bills of lading, and other relevant documents. They then make detailed calculations to determine the contributions each party should make. This process can be lengthy, often taking several months or even years to complete, especially for complex cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Determining Contributions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;6-determining-contributions&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#6-determining-contributions&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on the total value of the ship and the cargo, the average adjuster calculates the proportionate share that each stakeholder must contribute to cover the GA losses or expenses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Payment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;7-payment&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#7-payment&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once the adjustment is finalized, each stakeholder (or their insurers) is required to pay their determined share. Cargo owners who provided cash deposits will have those deposits applied toward their contributions, with any excess returned or any additional amounts billed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Marine Insurance:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;8-marine-insurance&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#8-marine-insurance&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Those parties who have marine insurance policies with GA coverage can submit their claims to their insurers. After verification, the insurer typically compensates the cargo or ship owner for their share of the GA expenditure, as per the terms of the policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Resolution:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;9-resolution&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#9-resolution&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once all contributions are collected and any damages or losses are compensated, the GA claim is resolved, and the incident is closed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s essential to note that while the concept of GA has its roots in ancient maritime custom, modern GA claims are often governed by the &lt;strong&gt;York-Antwerp Rules&lt;/strong&gt;, which provide standardized guidelines for declaring and adjusting GA. As such, parties involved in maritime shipping are well-advised to be familiar with these rules and ensure they have adequate insurance to cover potential GA claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cargo insurance covering General Average in Sea Freight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;cargo-insurance-covering-general-average-in-sea-freight&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#cargo-insurance-covering-general-average-in-sea-freight&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cargo insurance is a vital aspect of international trade, especially when goods are transported by sea. One of the risks that this insurance covers is the possibility of a General Average (GA) event. Here’s a detailed look at cargo insurance as it pertains to GA in sea freight:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Cargo Insurance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-is-cargo-insurance&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-cargo-insurance&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cargo insurance offers protection against physical damage to, or loss of, goods during shipping, whether by sea, land, or air. Given the myriad of risks associated with sea freight – from storms and collisions to piracy and jettisoning – cargo insurance provides a safeguard for shippers and consignees against financial losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Does Cargo Insurance Cover General Average?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;how-does-cargo-insurance-cover-general-average&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#how-does-cargo-insurance-cover-general-average&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coverage of Contribution&lt;/strong&gt;: In the event of a GA, all parties involved, including cargo owners, are required to contribute to the shared loss proportionally. If the cargo is insured, the insurance company will typically cover the policyholder’s (cargo owner’s) contribution. Without insurance, the cargo owner would be personally liable to cover this amount.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release of Cargo&lt;/strong&gt;: When a GA is declared, the cargo may be held at the port of discharge until the cargo owner provides a GA bond and possibly a cash deposit as a guarantee of their eventual contribution. An insured party can rely on their insurance company to provide this bond, ensuring the timely release of their cargo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional Costs&lt;/strong&gt;: GA-related costs might include salvage charges, damage repair, or other expenses incurred to preserve the voyage. A comprehensive cargo insurance policy will typically cover these additional costs, so the cargo owner doesn’t bear them out-of-pocket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points to Consider with Cargo Insurance and GA:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;key-points-to-consider-with-cargo-insurance-and-ga&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#key-points-to-consider-with-cargo-insurance-and-ga&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extent of Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Not all cargo insurance policies automatically cover General Average (GA).&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;It’s essential to ensure that General Average (GA) is explicitly included in the coverage when purchasing a policy, especially if the goods will be transported by sea.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valuation&lt;/strong&gt;: To guarantee full reimbursement in the event of a loss, the cargo should be appropriately valued in the insurance policy. Often, shippers choose to insure their cargo for its full value plus an additional percentage to cover potential additional costs, such as freight, duties, and potential profit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;York-Antwerp Rules&lt;/strong&gt;: Most GA claims are adjusted following the York-Antwerp Rules. Therefore, understanding how these rules apply and ensuring that the insurance policy aligns with them is crucial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deductibles&lt;/strong&gt;: Like other insurance types, cargo insurance may have deductibles, meaning the policyholder is responsible for covering a portion of the loss. Shippers should be aware of any deductibles and how they might apply in a GA situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Claims Process&lt;/strong&gt;: If a GA occurs, the policyholder should notify their insurer immediately, providing all relevant documentation. This ensures a smoother and faster claims process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the concept of General Average is ancient, its implications for modern sea freight are significant. As the global shipping industry continues to face both traditional and new challenges, having a cargo insurance policy that covers GA is more important than ever. It protects cargo owners from unexpected financial burdens and provides peace of mind in an industry fraught with unpredictability.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>York Antwerp Rules 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/partc/em303/averageadjustment/yar2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/partc/em303/averageadjustment/yar2016/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule of Interpretation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-of-interpretation&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-of-interpretation&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the adjustment of general average the following Rules shall apply to the exclusion of any law and practice inconsistent therewith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except as provided by the Rule Paramount and the numbered Rules, general average shall be adjusted according to the lettered Rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule Paramount&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-paramount&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-paramount&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In no case shall there be any allowance for sacrifice or expenditure unless reasonably made or incurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-a&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-a&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a general average act when, and only when, any extraordinary sacrifice or expenditure is intentionally and reasonably made or incurred for the common safety for the purpose of preserving from peril the property involved in a common maritime adventure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General average sacrifices and expenditures shall be borne by the different contributing interests on the basis hereinafter provided.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule B&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-b&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-b&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a common maritime adventure when one or more vessels are towing or pushing another vessel or vessels, provided that they are all involved in commercial activities and not in a salvage operation. When measures are taken to preserve the vessels and their cargoes, if any, from a common peril, these Rules shall apply.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the vessels are in common peril and one is disconnected either to increase the disconnecting vessel’s safety alone, or the safety of all vessels in the common maritime adventure, the disconnection will be a general average act.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where vessels involved in a common maritime adventure resort to a port or place of refuge, allowances under these Rules may be made in relation to each of the vessels. Subject to the provisions of paragraphs 3 and 4 of Rule G, allowances in general average shall cease at the time that the common maritime adventure comes to an end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-c&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-c&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only such losses, damages or expenses which are the direct consequence of the general average act shall be allowed as general average.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In no case shall there be any allowance in general average for losses, damages or expenses incurred in respect of damage to the environment or in consequence of the escape or release of pollutant substances from the property involved in the common maritime adventure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demurrage, loss of market, and any loss or damage sustained or expense incurred by reason of delay, whether on the voyage or subsequently, and any indirect loss whatsoever, shall not be allowed as general average.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule D&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-d&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-d&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rights to contribution in general average shall not be affected, though the event which gave rise to the sacrifice or expenditure may have been due to the fault of one of the parties to the common maritime adventure, but this shall not prejudice any remedies or defences which may be open against or to that party in respect of such fault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule E&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-e&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The onus of proof is upon the party claiming in general average to show that the loss or expense claimed is properly allowable as general average.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All  parties  to  the  common maritime  adventure shall,  as  soon  as  possible, supply particulars of value in respect of their contributory interest and, if claiming in general average, shall give notice in writing to the average adjuster of the loss or expense in respect of which they claim contribution, and supply evidence in support thereof.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Failing notification, or if any party does not supply particulars in support of a notified claim, within 12 months of the termination of the common maritime adventure or payment of the expense, the average adjuster shall be at liberty to estimate the extent of the allowance on the basis of the information available to the adjuster.  Particulars of value shall be provided within 12 months of the termination of the common maritime adventure, failing which the average adjuster shall be at liberty to estimate the contributory value on the same basis. Such estimates shall be communicated to the party in question in writing. Estimates may only be challenged within two months of receipt of the communication and only on the grounds that they are manifestly incorrect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any party to the common maritime adventure pursuing a recovery from a third party in respect of sacrifice or expenditure claimed in general average, shall so advise the average adjuster and, in the event that a recovery is achieved, shall supply to the average adjuster full particulars of the recovery within two months of receipt of the recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule F&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-f&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-f&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any additional expense incurred in place of another expense which would have been allowable as general average shall be deemed to be general average and so allowed without regard to the saving, if any, to other interests, but only up to the amount of the general average expense avoided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule G&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-g&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-g&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General average shall be adjusted as regards both loss and contribution upon the basis of values at the time and place when and where the common maritime adventure ends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This rule shall not affect the determination of the place at which the average adjustment is to be prepared.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a ship is at any port or place in circumstances which would give rise to an allowance in general average under the provisions of Rules X and XI, and the cargo or part thereof is forwarded to destination by other means, rights and liabilities in general average shall, subject to cargo interests being notified if practicable, remain as nearly as possible the same as they would have been in the absence of such forwarding, as if the common maritime adventure had continued in the original ship for so long as justifiable under the contract of carriage and the applicable law.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The proportion attaching to cargo of the allowances made in general average by reason of applying the third paragraph of this Rule shall be limited to the cost which would have been borne by the owners of cargo if the cargo had been forwarded at their expense. This limit shall not apply to any allowances made under Rule F.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.tdi_2.td-a-rec{text-align:center}.tdi_2.td-a-rec:not(.td-a-rec-no-translate){transform:translateZ(0)}.tdi_2 .td-element-style{z-index:-1}.tdi_2.td-a-rec-img{text-align:left}.tdi_2.td-a-rec-img img{margin:0 auto 0 0}@media (max-width:767px){.tdi_2.td-a-rec-img{text-align:center}} var td_screen_width = window.innerWidth; window.addEventListener(&amp;ldquo;load&amp;rdquo;, function(){ var placeAdEl = document.getElementById(&amp;ldquo;td-ad-placeholder&amp;rdquo;); if ( null !== placeAdEl &amp;amp;&amp;amp; td_screen_width &amp;gt;= 1140 ) { /* large monitors &lt;em&gt;/ var adEl = document.createElement(&amp;ldquo;ins&amp;rdquo;); placeAdEl.replaceWith(adEl); adEl.setAttribute(&amp;ldquo;class&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;adsbygoogle&amp;rdquo;); adEl.setAttribute(&amp;ldquo;style&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;display:inline-block;width:970px;height:250px&amp;rdquo;); adEl.setAttribute(&amp;ldquo;data-ad-client&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ca-pub-5596142290138833&amp;rdquo;); adEl.setAttribute(&amp;ldquo;data-ad-slot&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;4963775542&amp;rdquo;); (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({}); } });window.addEventListener(&amp;ldquo;load&amp;rdquo;, function(){ var placeAdEl = document.getElementById(&amp;ldquo;td-ad-placeholder&amp;rdquo;); if ( null !== placeAdEl &amp;amp;&amp;amp; td_screen_width &amp;gt;= 1019 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; td_screen_width &amp;lt; 1140 ) { /&lt;/em&gt; landscape tablets &lt;em&gt;/ var adEl = document.createElement(&amp;ldquo;ins&amp;rdquo;); placeAdEl.replaceWith(adEl); adEl.setAttribute(&amp;ldquo;class&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;adsbygoogle&amp;rdquo;); adEl.setAttribute(&amp;ldquo;style&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;display:inline-block;width:970px;height:250px&amp;rdquo;); adEl.setAttribute(&amp;ldquo;data-ad-client&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ca-pub-5596142290138833&amp;rdquo;); adEl.setAttribute(&amp;ldquo;data-ad-slot&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;4963775542&amp;rdquo;); (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({}); } });window.addEventListener(&amp;ldquo;load&amp;rdquo;, function(){ var placeAdEl = document.getElementById(&amp;ldquo;td-ad-placeholder&amp;rdquo;); if ( null !== placeAdEl &amp;amp;&amp;amp; td_screen_width &amp;gt;= 768 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; td_screen_width &amp;lt; 1019 ) { /&lt;/em&gt; portrait tablets &lt;em&gt;/ var adEl = document.createElement(&amp;ldquo;ins&amp;rdquo;); placeAdEl.replaceWith(adEl); adEl.setAttribute(&amp;ldquo;class&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;adsbygoogle&amp;rdquo;); adEl.setAttribute(&amp;ldquo;style&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;display:inline-block;width:970px;height:250px&amp;rdquo;); adEl.setAttribute(&amp;ldquo;data-ad-client&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ca-pub-5596142290138833&amp;rdquo;); adEl.setAttribute(&amp;ldquo;data-ad-slot&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;4963775542&amp;rdquo;); (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({}); } });window.addEventListener(&amp;ldquo;load&amp;rdquo;, function(){ var placeAdEl = document.getElementById(&amp;ldquo;td-ad-placeholder&amp;rdquo;); if ( null !== placeAdEl &amp;amp;&amp;amp; td_screen_width &amp;lt; 768 ) { /&lt;/em&gt; Phones */ var adEl = document.createElement(&amp;ldquo;ins&amp;rdquo;); placeAdEl.replaceWith(adEl); adEl.setAttribute(&amp;ldquo;class&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;adsbygoogle&amp;rdquo;); adEl.setAttribute(&amp;ldquo;style&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;display:inline-block;width:320px;height:50px&amp;rdquo;); adEl.setAttribute(&amp;ldquo;data-ad-client&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ca-pub-5596142290138833&amp;rdquo;); adEl.setAttribute(&amp;ldquo;data-ad-slot&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;4963775542&amp;rdquo;); (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({}); } });&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule I – Jettison of Cargo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-i--jettison-of-cargo&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-i--jettison-of-cargo&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;No jettison of cargo shall be allowed as general average, unless such cargo is carried in accordance with the recognised custom of the trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule II – Loss or Damage by Sacrifices for the Common Safety&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-ii--loss-or-damage-by-sacrifices-for-the-common-safety&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-ii--loss-or-damage-by-sacrifices-for-the-common-safety&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Loss of or damage to the property involved in the common maritime adventure by or in consequence of a sacrifice made for the common safety, and by water which goes down a ship’s hatches opened or other opening made for the purpose of making a jettison for the common safety, shall be allowed as general average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule III – Extinguishing Fire on Shipboard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-iii--extinguishing-fire-on-shipboard&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-iii--extinguishing-fire-on-shipboard&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Damage done to a ship and cargo, or either of them, by water or otherwise, including damage by beaching or scuttling a burning ship, in extinguishing a fire on board the ship, shall be allowed as general average; except that no allowance shall be made for damage by smoke however caused or by heat of the fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule IV – Cutting Away Wreck&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-iv--cutting-away-wreck&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-iv--cutting-away-wreck&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Loss or damage sustained by cutting away wreck or parts of the ship which have been previously carried away or are effectively lost by accident shall not be allowed as general average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule V – Voluntary Stranding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-v--voluntary-stranding&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-v--voluntary-stranding&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When a ship is intentionally run on shore for the common safety, whether or not she might have been driven on shore, the consequent loss or damage to the property involved in the common maritime adventure shall be allowed in general average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule VI – Salvage Remuneration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-vi--salvage-remuneration&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-vi--salvage-remuneration&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(a)&lt;/strong&gt; Expenditure incurred by the parties to the common maritime adventure in the nature of salvage, whether under contract or otherwise, shall be allowed in general average provided that the salvage operations were carried out for the purpose of preserving from peril the property involved in the common maritime adventure and subject to the provisions of paragraphs (b), (c) and (d)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(b)&lt;/strong&gt; Notwithstanding (a) above, where the parties to the common maritime adventure have separate contractual or legal liability to salvors, salvage shall only be allowed should any of the following arise:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(i)&lt;/strong&gt; there is a subsequent accident or other circumstances resulting in loss or damage to property during the voyage that results in significant differences between salved and contributory values,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ii)&lt;/strong&gt; there are significant general average sacrifices,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(iii)&lt;/strong&gt; salved values are  manifestly incorrect and  there is  a  significantly incorrect apportionment of salvage expenses,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(iv)&lt;/strong&gt; any of the parties to the salvage has paid a significant proportion of salvage due from another party,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(v)&lt;/strong&gt; a significant proportion of the parties have satisfied the salvage claim on substantially different terms, no regard being had to interest, currency correction or legal costs of either the salvor or the contributing interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(c)&lt;/strong&gt; Salvage expenditures referred to in paragraph (a) above shall include any salvage remuneration in which the skill and efforts of the salvors in preventing or minimising damage to the environment such as is referred to in Article 13 paragraph 1(b) of the International Convention on Salvage, 1989 have been taken into account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(d)&lt;/strong&gt; Special compensation payable to a salvor by the shipowner under Article 14 of the International Convention on Salvage, 1989 to the extent specified in paragraph 4 of that Article or under any other provision similar in substance (such as SCOPIC) shall not be allowed in general average and shall not be considered a salvage expenditure as referred to in paragraph (a) of this Rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule VII – Damage to Machinery and Boilers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-vii--damage-to-machinery-and-boilers&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-vii--damage-to-machinery-and-boilers&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Damage caused to any machinery and boilers of a ship which is ashore and in a position of peril, in endeavouring to refloat, shall be allowed in general average when shown to have arisen from an actual intention to float the ship for the common safety at the risk of such damage; but where a ship is afloat no loss or damage caused by working the propelling machinery and boilers shall in any circumstances be allowed as general average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule VIII – Expenses Lightening a Ship when Ashore, and Consequent Damage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-viii--expenses-lightening-a-ship-when-ashore-and-consequent-damage&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-viii--expenses-lightening-a-ship-when-ashore-and-consequent-damage&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When a ship is ashore and cargo and ship’s fuel and stores or any of them are discharged as a general average act, the extra cost of lightening, lighter hire and reshipping (if incurred), and any loss or damage to the property involved in the common maritime adventure in consequence thereof, shall be allowed as general average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule IX – Cargo, Ship’s Materials and Stores Used for Fuel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-ix--cargo-ships-materials-and-stores-used-for-fuel&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-ix--cargo-ships-materials-and-stores-used-for-fuel&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cargo, ship’s materials and stores, or any of them, necessarily used for fuel for the common safety at a time of peril shall be allowed as general average, but when such an allowance is made for the cost of ship’s materials and stores the general average shall be credited with the estimated cost of the fuel which would otherwise have been consumed in prosecuting the intended voyage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule X – Expenses at Port of Refuge, etc.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-x--expenses-at-port-of-refuge-etc&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-x--expenses-at-port-of-refuge-etc&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(a) (i)&lt;/strong&gt; When a ship shall have entered a port or place of refuge or shall have returned to her port or place of loading in consequence of accident, sacrifice or other extraordinary circumstances which render that necessary for the common safety, the expenses of entering such port or place shall be allowed as general average; and when she shall have sailed thence with her original cargo, or a part of it, the corresponding expenses of leaving such port or place consequent upon such entry or return shall likewise be allowed as general average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ii)&lt;/strong&gt; When a ship is at any port or place of refuge and is necessarily removed to another port or place because repairs cannot be carried out in the first port or place, the provisions of this Rule shall be applied to the second port or place as if it were a port or place of refuge and the cost of such removal including temporary repairs and towage shall be allowed as general average. The provisions of Rule XI shall be applied to the prolongation of the voyage occasioned by such removal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(b) (i)&lt;/strong&gt; The cost of handling on board or discharging cargo, fuel or stores, whether at a port or place of loading, call or refuge, shall be allowed as general average when the handling or discharge was necessary for the common safety or to enable damage to the ship caused by sacrifice or accident to be repaired, if the repairs were necessary for the safe prosecution of the voyage, except in  cases where the damage to  the ship is discovered at a port or place of loading or call without any accident or other extraordinary circumstances connected with such damage having taken place during the voyage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ii)&lt;/strong&gt; The cost of handling on board or discharging cargo, fuel or stores shall not be allowable as general average when incurred solely for the purpose of restowage due to shifting during the voyage, unless such restowage is necessary for the common safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(c)&lt;/strong&gt; Whenever the cost of handling or discharging cargo, fuel or stores is allowable as general average, the costs of storage, including insurance if reasonably incurred, reloading and stowing of such cargo, fuel or stores shall likewise be allowed as general average.   The provisions of Rule XI  shall apply to  the extra period of detention occasioned by such reloading or restowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(d)&lt;/strong&gt; When the ship is condemned or does not proceed on her original voyage, storage expenses shall be allowed as general average only up to the date of the ship’s condemnation or of the abandonment of the voyage or up to the date of completion of discharge of cargo if the condemnation or abandonment takes place before that date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule XI – Wages and Maintenance of Crew and Other Expenses Putting in to and at a&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;P****ort of Refuge, etc.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-xi--wages-and-maintenance-of-crew-and-other-expenses-putting-in-to-and-at-a-port-of-refuge-etc&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-xi--wages-and-maintenance-of-crew-and-other-expenses-putting-in-to-and-at-a-port-of-refuge-etc&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(a)&lt;/strong&gt; Wages and maintenance of master, officers and crew reasonably incurred and fuel and stores consumed during the prolongation of the voyage occasioned by a ship entering a port or place of refuge or returning to her port or place of loading shall be allowed as general average when the expenses of entering such port or place are allowable in general average in accordance with Rule X(a).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(b) (i)&lt;/strong&gt; When a ship shall have entered or been detained in any port or place in consequence of accident, sacrifice or other extra-ordinary circumstances which render that entry or detention necessary for the common safety, or to enable damage to the ship caused by sacrifice or accident to be repaired, if the repairs were necessary for the safe prosecution of the voyage, the wages and maintenance of the master, officers and crew reasonably incurred during the extra period of detention in such port or place until the ship shall or should have been made ready to proceed upon her voyage, shall be allowed in general average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ii)&lt;/strong&gt; Fuel and stores consumed during the extra period of detention shall be allowed as general average, except such fuel and stores as are consumed in effecting repairs not allowable in general average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(iii)&lt;/strong&gt; Port charges incurred during the extra period of detention shall likewise be allowed as general average except such charges as are incurred solely by reason of repairs not allowable in general average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(iv)&lt;/strong&gt; Provided that when damage to the ship is discovered at a port or place of loading or call without any accident or other extraordinary circumstance connected with such damage having taken place during the voyage, then the wages and maintenance of master, officers and crew and fuel and stores consumed and port charges incurred during the extra detention for repairs to damages so discovered shall not be allowable as general average, even if the repairs are necessary for the safe prosecution of the voyage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(v)&lt;/strong&gt; When the ship is condemned or does not proceed on her original voyage, the wages and maintenance of the master, officers and crew and fuel and stores consumed and port charges shall be allowed as general average only up to the date of the ship’s condemnation or of the abandonment of the voyage or up to the date of completion of discharge of cargo if the condemnation or abandonment takes place before that date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(c) (i)&lt;/strong&gt; For the purpose of these Rules wages shall include all payments made to or for the benefit of the master, officers and crew, whether such payments be imposed by law upon the shipowners or be made under the terms of articles of employment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ii)&lt;/strong&gt; For the purpose of these Rules, port charges shall include all customary or additional expenses incurred for the common safety or to enable a vessel to enter or remain at a port of refuge or call in the circumstances outlined in Rule XI(b)(i).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(d)&lt;/strong&gt; The cost of measures undertaken to prevent or minimise damage to the environment shall be allowed in general average when incurred in any or all of the following circumstances:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(i)&lt;/strong&gt; as part of an operation performed for the common safety which, had it been undertaken by a party outside the common maritime adventure, would have entitled such party to a salvage reward;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ii)&lt;/strong&gt; as a condition of entry into or departure from any port or place in the circumstances prescribed in Rule X(a);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(iii)&lt;/strong&gt; as  a  condition  of  remaining  at  any  port  or  place  in  the  circumstances prescribed in Rule XI(b), provided that when there is an actual escape or release of pollutant substances, the cost of any additional measures required on that account to prevent or  minimise pollution or  environmental damage shall not  be allowed as general average;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(iv)&lt;/strong&gt; necessarily in connection with the handling on board, discharging, storing or reloading of cargo, fuel or stores whenever the cost of those operations is allowable as general average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule XII – Damage to Cargo in Discharging, etc.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-xii--damage-to-cargo-in-discharging-etc&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-xii--damage-to-cargo-in-discharging-etc&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Damage  to  or  loss  of  cargo,  fuel  or  stores  sustained  in  consequence of  their handling, discharging, storing, reloading and stowing shall be allowed as general average, when and only when the cost of those measures respectively is allowed as general average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule XIII – Deductions from Cost of Repairs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-xiii--deductions-from-cost-of-repairs&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-xiii--deductions-from-cost-of-repairs&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(a)&lt;/strong&gt; Repairs to be allowed in general average shall not be subject to deductions in respect of “new for old” where old material or parts are replaced by new unless the ship is over fifteen years old in which case there shall be a deduction of one third. The deductions shall be regulated by the age of the ship from the 31st December of the year of completion of construction to the date of the general average act, except for insulation, life and similar boats, communications and navigational apparatus and equipment, machinery and boilers for which the deductions shall be regulated by the age of the particular parts to which they apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(b)&lt;/strong&gt; The deductions shall be made only from the cost of the new material or parts when finished and ready to be installed in the ship. No deduction shall be made in respect of provisions, stores, anchors and chain cables. Drydock and slipway dues and costs of shifting the ship shall be allowed in full.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(c)&lt;/strong&gt; The costs of cleaning, painting or coating of bottom shall not be allowed in general average unless the bottom has been painted or coated within the 24 months preceding the date of the general average act in which case one half of such costs shall be allowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule XIV – Temporary Repairs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-xiv--temporary-repairs&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-xiv--temporary-repairs&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(a)&lt;/strong&gt; Where temporary repairs are effected to a ship at a port of loading, call or refuge, for the common safety, or of damage caused by general average sacrifice, the cost of such repairs shall be allowed as general average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(b)&lt;/strong&gt; Where temporary repairs of accidental damage are effected in order to enable the common maritime adventure to be completed, the cost of such repairs shall be allowed as general average without regard to the saving, if any, to other interests, but only up to the saving in expense which would have been incurred and allowed in general average if such repairs had not been effected there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(c)&lt;/strong&gt; No deductions “new for  old” shall be made from the cost of temporary repairs allowable as general average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule XV – Loss of Freight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-xv--loss-of-freight&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-xv--loss-of-freight&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Loss of freight arising from damage to or loss of cargo shall be allowed as general average, either when caused by a general average act, or when the damage to or loss of cargo is so allowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deduction shall be made from the amount of gross freight lost, of the charges which the owner thereof would have incurred to earn such freight, but has, in consequence of the sacrifice, not incurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule XVI – Amount to be Allowed for Cargo Lost or Damaged by Sacrifice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-xvi--amount-to-be-allowed-for-cargo-lost-or-damaged-by-sacrifice&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-xvi--amount-to-be-allowed-for-cargo-lost-or-damaged-by-sacrifice&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(a) (i)&lt;/strong&gt; The amount to be allowed as general average for damage to or loss of cargo sacrificed shall be the loss which has been sustained thereby based on the value at the time of discharge, ascertained from the commercial invoice rendered to the receiver or if there is no such invoice from the shipped value. Such commercial invoice may be deemed by the average adjuster to reflect the value at the time of discharge irrespective of the place of final delivery under the contract of carriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ii)&lt;/strong&gt; The value at the time of discharge shall include the cost of insurance and freight except insofar as such freight is at the risk of interests other than the cargo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(b)&lt;/strong&gt; When cargo so damaged is sold and the amount of the damage has not been otherwise agreed, the loss to be allowed in general average shall be the difference between the net proceeds of sale and the net sound value as computed in the first paragraph of this Rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule XVII – Contributory Values&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-xvii--contributory-values&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-xvii--contributory-values&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(a) (i)&lt;/strong&gt; The contribution to a general average shall be made upon the actual net values of the property at the termination of the common maritime adventure except that the value of cargo shall be the value at the time of discharge, ascertained from the commercial invoice rendered to the receiver or if there is no such invoice from the shipped value. Such commercial invoice may be deemed by the average adjuster to reflect the value at the time of discharge irrespective of the place of final delivery under the contract of carriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ii)&lt;/strong&gt; The value of the cargo shall include the cost of insurance and freight unless and insofar as such freight is at the risk of interests other than the cargo, deducting therefrom any  loss  or  damage suffered by  the  cargo  prior  to  or  at  the  time  of discharge. Any cargo may be excluded from contributing to  general average should the average adjuster consider that the cost of including it in the adjustment would be likely to be disproportionate to its eventual contribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(iii)&lt;/strong&gt; The  value  of  the  ship  shall  be  assessed  without  taking  into  account  the beneficial or detrimental effect of any demise or time charterparty to which the ship may be committed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(b)&lt;/strong&gt; To these values shall be added the amount allowed as general average for property sacrificed, if not already included, deduction being made from the freight and passage money at risk of such charges and crew’s wages as would not have been incurred in earning the freight had the ship and cargo been totally lost at the date of the general average act and have not been allowed as general average; deduction being also made from the value of the property of all extra charges incurred in respect thereof subsequently to the general average act, except such charges as are allowed in general average. Where payment for salvage services has not been allowed as general average by reason of paragraph (b) of Rule VI, deductions in respect of payment for salvage services shall be limited to the amount paid to the salvors including interest and salvors’ costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(c)&lt;/strong&gt; In the circumstances envisaged in the third paragraph of Rule G, the cargo and other property shall contribute on the basis of its value upon delivery at original destination unless sold or otherwise disposed of short of that destination, and the ship shall contribute upon its actual net value at the time of completion of discharge of cargo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(d)&lt;/strong&gt; Where cargo is sold short of destination, however, it shall contribute upon the actual net proceeds of sale, with the addition of any amount allowed as general average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(e)&lt;/strong&gt; Mails,  passengers’  luggage  and  accompanied  personal  effects  and  accompanied private motor vehicles shall not contribute to general average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule XVIII – Damage to Ship&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-xviii--damage-to-ship&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-xviii--damage-to-ship&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The amount to be allowed as general average for damage or loss to the ship, her machinery and/or gear caused by a general average act shall be as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(a)&lt;/strong&gt; When repaired or replaced,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual reasonable cost of repairing or replacing such damage or loss, subject to deductions in accordance with Rule XIII;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(b)&lt;/strong&gt; When not repaired or replaced,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasonable depreciation arising from such damage or loss, but not exceeding the estimated cost of repairs.  But where the ship is an actual total loss or when the cost of repairs of the damage would exceed the value of the ship when repaired, the amount to be allowed as general average shall be the difference between the estimated sound value of the ship after deducting therefrom the estimated cost of repairing damage which is not general average and the value of the ship in her damaged state which may be measured by the net proceeds of sale, if any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule XIX – Undeclared or Wrongfully Declared Cargo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-xix--undeclared-or-wrongfully-declared-cargo&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-xix--undeclared-or-wrongfully-declared-cargo&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(a)&lt;/strong&gt; Damage or loss caused to goods loaded without the knowledge of the shipowner or his agent or to goods wilfully misdescribed at the time of shipment shall not be allowed as general average, but such goods shall remain liable to contribute, if saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(b)&lt;/strong&gt; Where goods have been wrongfully declared at the time of shipment at a value which is lower than their real value, any general average loss or damage shall be allowed on the basis of their declared value, but such goods shall contribute on the basis of their actual value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule XX – Provision of Funds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-xx--provision-of-funds&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-xx--provision-of-funds&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(a)&lt;/strong&gt; The capital loss sustained by the owners of goods sold for the purpose of raising funds to defray general average disbursements shall be allowed in general average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(b)&lt;/strong&gt; The cost of insuring general average disbursements shall be allowed in general average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule XXI – Interest on Losses Allowed in General Average&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-xxi--interest-on-losses-allowed-in-general-average&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-xxi--interest-on-losses-allowed-in-general-average&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(a)&lt;/strong&gt; Interest shall be allowed on expenditure, sacrifices and allowances in general average until  three months after  the  date  of  issue of  the  general average adjustment, due allowance being made for any payment on account by the contributory interests or from the general average deposit fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(b)&lt;/strong&gt; The rate  for calculating interest accruing during each calendar year shall be the 12- month ICE LIBOR for the currency in which the adjustment is prepared, as announced on the first banking day of that calendar year, increased by four percentage points. If the adjustment is prepared in a currency for which no ICE LIBOR is announced, the rate shall be the 12-month US Dollar ICE LIBOR, increased by four percentage points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule XXII – Treatment of Cash Deposits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-xxii--treatment-of-cash-deposits&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-xxii--treatment-of-cash-deposits&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(a)&lt;/strong&gt; Where cash deposits have been collected in respect of general average, salvage or special charges, such sums shall be remitted forthwith to the average adjuster who shall deposit the sums into a special account, earning interest where possible, in the name of the average adjuster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(b)&lt;/strong&gt; The special account shall be constituted in accordance with the law regarding client or third party funds applicable in the domicile of the average adjuster. The account shall be held separately from the average adjuster’s own funds, in trust or in compliance with similar rules of law providing for the administration of the funds of third parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(c)&lt;/strong&gt; The sums so deposited, together with accrued interest, if any, shall be held as security for payment to the parties entitled thereto, of the general average, salvage or special charges in respect of which the deposits have been collected. Payments on account or refunds of deposits may only be made when such payments are certified in writing by the average adjuster and notified to the depositor requesting their approval.  Upon the receipt of the depositor’s approval, or in the absence of such approval within a period of 90 days, the average adjuster may deduct the amount of the payment on account or the final contribution from the deposit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(d)&lt;/strong&gt; All deposits and payments or refunds shall  be without prejudice to the ultimate liability of the parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule XXIII – Time Bar for Contributing to General Average&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rule-xxiii--time-bar-for-contributing-to-general-average&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-xxiii--time-bar-for-contributing-to-general-average&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(a)&lt;/strong&gt; Subject always to any mandatory rule on time limitation contained in any applicable law:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(i)&lt;/strong&gt; Any rights to general average contribution including any rights to claim under general average bonds  and  guarantees, shall  be  extinguished unless an  action  is brought by the party claiming such contribution within a period of one year after the date upon which the general average adjustment is issued.  However, in no case shall such an action be brought after six years from the date of termination of the common maritime adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ii)&lt;/strong&gt; These periods may be extended if the parties so agree after the termination of the common maritime adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(b)&lt;/strong&gt; This rule shall not apply as between the parties to the general average and their respective insurers.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
